♪ 산들은 음악소리로
The hills are alive
With the sound of music
♪ 살아 움직인다네
♪ 수 천년 동안 불러온
With songs they have sung
For a thousand years
♪ 노래들과 함께
The hills fill my heart
♪ 산들은 그 음악소리로
With the sound of music
♪ 내 마음을 채운다네
My heart wants to sing
Every song it hears
♪ 산들의 모든 노래를
불러보고 싶어
My heart wants to beat like the wings
Of the birds that rise
♪ 호수에서 나무로 나는
새의 날개 짓처럼
From the lake to the trees
♪ 내 마음은 뛰놀고
♪ 미풍에 실려오는
종소리처럼
My heart wants to sigh
Like a chime that flies
From a church on a breeze
♪ 내 마음도 흔들리네
To laugh like a brook
When it trips and falls
♪ 시냇물이 돌 위로
흩어지는 소리처럼
Over stones on its way
♪ 맑고 경쾌하게
To sing through the night
♪ 밤새 기원하는 시인과 같이
Like a lark who is learning to pray
♪ 함께 노래하고파
I go to the hills
♪ 마음이 외로워질 때면
When my heart is lonely
♪ 이곳으로 올라와
I know I will hear
♪ 여기서 아름다운
What I've heard before
♪ 추억의 노래를 듣겠지
My heart will be blessed
♪ 그 음악소리
With the sound of music
♪ 내 맘에 축복이 되어
And I'll sing
♪ 한번 더
Once more
♪ 불러보고 싶어
사운드 오브 뮤직
쥴리 앤드류스
크리스토퍼 플러머
리처드 헤이든
엘리아놀 파커
감독 : 로버트 와이즈
오스트리아, 짤즈부르크
1939년대 마지막 황금기
♪ 할렐루야, 할렐루야
Hallelujah, hallelujah
- 원장 수녀님
- 베르니스 수녀
- Reverend Mother.
- Sister Bernice.
- I simply cannot find her.
- Maria?
- 어디 있는지 못 찾겠어요
- 마리아?
She's missing again.
또 사라졌어요
We should've put a cowbell
around her neck.
목에 방울이라도 달아둘걸
Have you tried the barn? You know
how much she adores the animals.
헛간에 가 봤어요?
동물들을 무척 좋아하잖아요
I have looked everywhere.
In all of the usual places.
갈만한 곳은 다 찾아봤어요
Sister, considering it's Maria...
마리아라면
...I suggest you look in someplace
unusual.
특이한 곳을 찾아봐야
할 거예요
Well, Reverend Mother...
원장 수녀님
...I hope this new infraction ends
whatever doubts...
매번 이런 일이 있는데도
...you may still have
about Maria's future here.
그냥 놔두실 건가요?
I always try to keep faith
in my doubts, Sister Berthe.
난 의심 속에서도 항상
믿음을 지키려고 해요
After all, the wool of a black sheep
is just as warm.
말썽부리는 양이라도
털은 따뜻하니까요
We are not talking about sheep,
black or white, Sister Margaretta.
말썽쟁이든 아니든
양 얘기가 아니에요
Of all the candidates for
the novitiate, Maria is the least--
수련 수녀들 중에서
가장 부적격해-
Children, children.
자매님들, 제발
We were speculating about
the qualifications of our postulants.
후보자들의 질적인 면은
숙고해 봤습니다
The Mistress of Novices
and the Mistress of Postulants...
견습생 담당 수녀님들의
...were trying to help me
by expressing opposite points of view.
의견이 서로 엇갈리는데
Tell me, Sister Catherine,
what do you think of Maria?
캐서린 수녀는 마리아를
어떻게 생각해요?
She's a wonderful girl,
some of the time.
아주 훌륭해요,
가끔이긴 하지만
- 아가사 수녀는?
- 호감을 주긴 하지만
- Sister Agatha?
- It's very easy to like Maria...
...except when it's difficult.
좀 별난 데가 있어요
- And you, Sister Sophia?
- Oh, I love her very dearly.
- 소피아 수녀는?
- 사랑스럽긴 하지만
But she always seems to be
in trouble, doesn't she?
말썽이 너무 많아요
Exactly what I say.
♪ 제가 말한 대로예요
She climbs a tree and scrapes her knee
♪ 나무에 올라가 무릎과
Her dress has got a tear
♪ 옷이 엉망이 되고
She waltzes on her way to Mass
And whistles on the stair
♪ 미사에 갈 때
춤추고 휘파람을 불며
And underneath her wimple
She has curlers in her hair
♪ 두건 안에 곱슬머리를
감추고 있죠
I've even heard her singing
In the abbey
♪ 수도원 안에서도
노랠 부르고
She's always late for chapel
♪ 미사 시간엔 늘 지각이고
But her penitence is real
♪ 하지만 참회는 진실 되죠
She's always late for everything
♪ 모든 일에 지각이에요
Except for every meal
♪ 식사때를 제외하고는
♪ 이런 말 하긴 싫지만
확실히 느끼는 건데
I hate to have to say it
But I very firmly feel
♪ 마리아는 수도원엔
안 어울려요
Maria's not an asset to the abbey
I'd like to say a word in her behalf
♪ 그녀를 위한 변론이
있어요
Say it, Sister Margaretta.
♪ 말해봐요
Maria makes me laugh
♪ 마리아는 날 웃게 해요
♪ 마리아의 문제를 어떻게 풀까?
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you catch a cloud
And pin it down?
♪ 그녀를 어떻게 붙잡아 놓을까?
How do you find a word
That means Maria?
♪ 그녀를 뭐라고 표현할까요?
A flibbertigibbet
♪ 수다쟁이
- A will-o'-the-wisp
- A clown
- ♪ 사람을 홀려요
- ♪ 어릿광대
Many a thing you know
You'd like to tell her
♪ 그녀에게 할 말도 많고
Many a thing she ought to understand
♪ 그녀가 알아야 할 것도
많겠지
But how do you make her stay
And listen to all you say?
♪ 그녀를 데려다 어떻게
말을 듣게 만들죠?
♪ 모래 위의 파도를 어떻게
잠재울까요?
How do you keep a wave
Upon the sand?
♪ 마리아의 문제를
어떻게 하죠?
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you hold a moonbeam
♪ 달빛을 어떻게 손안에
In your hand?
♪ 넣을 수 있을까?
When I'm with her I'm confused
Out of focus and bemused
♪ 함께 있으면
혼란스럽고 멍해져
And I never know exactly where I am
♪ 정신이 없어요
- Unpredictable as weather
- She's as flighty as a feather
- ♪ 예측할 수 없는 날씨 같고
- ♪ 변덕스럽죠
- She's a darling
- She's a demon
- ♪ 사랑스럽기도 하고
- ♪ 악마이기도해요
She's a lamb
♪ 그녀는 양이에요
She'll out pester any pest
Drive a hornet from its nest
♪ 골칫거리에다
말썽만 피우죠
She can throw a whirling dervish
Out of whirl
♪ 금욕도 거부할 거예요
- She is gentle, she is wild
- She's a riddle, she's a child
- ♪ 기도는 거칠고도 부드럽고
- ♪ 의문투성이지만 어린애 같고
- She's a headache
- She's an angel
- 골칫거리예요
- 천사죠
She's a girl
♪ 그저 여자일 뿐이에요
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
♪ 마리아의 문제를 어떻게 할까?
How do you catch a cloud
And pin it down?
♪ 뜬구름 같으니 어떻게 잡을까?
How do you find a word
That means Maria?
♪ 어떤 말로 표현할 수 있을까?
- A flibbertigibbet
- A will-o'-the-wisp
- ♪ 수다쟁이
- ♪ 사람을 홀려요
A clown
♪ 어릿광대
♪ 그녀에게 할 말도 많고
Many a thing you know
You'd like to tell her
♪ 그녀가 알아야 할 것도
많겠지
Many a thing she ought to understand
- But how do you make her stay?
- And listen to all you say?
- ♪ 어떻게 붙잡아 놓을까?
- ♪ 어떻게 말을 듣게 할까요?
How do you keep a wave
Upon the sand?
♪ 모래 위의 파도를 어떻게
잠재울까요?
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
♪ 마리아 문제를 어떻게 할까?
How do you hold a moonbeam
♪ 달빛을 어떻게 손안에
In your hand?
♪ 넣을 수 있을까?
You may go in now, Maria.
들어가 봐요, 마리아
Come here, my child.
어서 와요
Now sit down.
이리로 앉지
Reverend Mother, I'm sorry.
I couldn't help myself.
원장수녀님, 죄송해요
어쩔 수 없었어요
- The hills were beckoning and before--
- Dear.
- 산들이 오라 손짓하는 바람에-
- 안심해
I haven't summoned you for apologies.
죄를 고하라고 호출한 게 아나야
Please let me ask for forgiveness.
용서를 구하게 해 주세요
If you'll feel better.
그래서 마음이 편하다면
Yes, you see,
the sky was so blue today...
하늘은 맑고
모든 것이 푸르고
...and everything was so green and
fragrant, I had to be a part of it.
향기로워
저도 일부가 되어
The Untersberg led me higher like
it wanted me to go through the clouds.
구름위로 높이
오르는 것 같았어요
Suppose darkness had come
and you were lost?
어두워져 길을 잃게되면
어쩌려고?
Mother, I could never be lost
up there.
절대 길을 잃진 않아요
That's my mountain.
I was brought up on it.
거긴 제 산인걸요
거기서 자랐어요
It was the mountain that led me
to you.
그 산이 여기로 보냈죠
When I was a child,
I would come down and climb a tree...
어렸을 때 나무에 올라가
이곳을
...and look in your garden.
내려다보곤 했어요
I'd see the sisters at work
and hear them sing.
일하는 것과
저녁 찬송 모습을
Which brings me to another
transgression, Reverend Mother.
오늘 규율 하나를
위반했어요
I was singing out there today.
허락 없이 또 노래를 했죠
Only in the abbey do we have rules
about postulants singing.
수도원 안에선
견습 수녀의 노래를 금해요
I can't stop wherever I am.
전 어디 있든 노래를 하고
Worse, I can't seem to stop
saying things.
생각이나 느낌도
Everything I think and feel.
다 말해 버리는 걸요
Some call that "honesty."
솔직해서 그래요
Oh, but it's terrible,
Reverend Mother!
끔찍할 정도예요
You know how Sister Berthe makes me
kiss the floor after a disagreement?
베르테 수녀님과는
늘 이견이 있어요
Lately, I kiss the floor when I see
her coming, just to save time.
이젠 만나면 피해 버려요
시간 낭비니까요
Maria...
마리아!
...when you saw us over the wall
and longed to be with us...
수도원에 자원하면서
...that didn't mean you were prepared
for the way we live here, did it?
수녀가 될 준비는
부족했던 것 같아요
No, Mother, but I pray and I try.
하지만 기도하고 노력하고
And I am learning. I really am.
배우고 있어요
What is the most important lesson
you have learned here?
여기서 배운 가장 중요한
교훈이 뭐지?
To find out what is the will of God
and do it wholeheartedly.
주님 뜻을 따라
마음을 다해 행하는 거죠
Maria...
마리아
...it seems to be God's will
that you leave us.
떠나는 것이 주님 뜻 같아요
- Leave?
- Only for a while.
- 떠나다뇨?
- 잠시 동안만이야
No, Mother!
Please don't send me away!
제발,
보내지 마세요!
This is where I belong. It's my home,
my family. It's my life.
여긴 내가 있을 곳이에요
내 집, 가족, 내 삶이죠
- Are you truly ready for it?
- Yes, I am.
- 수녀가 될 준비가 됐나?
- 그럼요
If you go out into the world for a time,
knowing what we expect of you...
잠시 세상에 나가 원하는 게
뭔지 찾아보도록 해요
...you will find out
if you can expect it of yourself.
자신에게 맞는 걸 말이에요
I know what you expect, Mother,
and I can do it! I promise I can!
원하는 걸 알아요
해낼 수도 있고요
Yes, Mother.
알겠어요
If it is God's will.
하나님의 뜻이라면
There is a family near Salzburg that
needs a governess until September.
짤즈버그에서 9월까지
가정교사를 구하더군
- September?
- For seven children.
- 9월까지요?
- 아이들은 일곱 명
Seven children?!
일곱 명?
Do you like children?
얘들을 좋아하잖아?
Well, yes, but seven!
하지만 일곱 명씩이나!
I will tell Captain von Trapp
to expect you tomorrow.
트랩 대령에게
내일 간다고 전하지
Captain?
대령이오?
A retired officer of the Imperial Navy.
A fine man and a brave one.
해군을 제대한
용감하고 훌륭한 분이지
His wife died,
and he is alone with the children.
몇 년 전 아내를 잃고
아이들과 살고 있는데
I understand he has had a difficult
time keeping a governess there.
가정교사를 잡아 두는 게
힘든 모양이야
Why difficult, Reverend Mother?
왜 힘들죠?
The Lord will show you
in his own good time.
하나님께서 때가 되면
알려주실 거야
When the Lord closes a door...
주님은 한쪽 문을 닫으면
...somewhere he opens a window.
다른 쪽 문을 여신다
What will this day be like?
♪ 오늘은 과연 어떻게 될까?
I wonder
♪ 정말 궁금해
What will my future be?
♪ 내 미래는 어떻게 될까?
I wonder
♪ 정말 궁금해
It could be so exciting
♪ 바깥 세상은
To be out in the world
To be free
♪ 자유롭고 신나는 곳
My heart should be wildly rejoicing
♪ 내 마음은 즐거워야 할텐데
Oh, what's the matter with me?
♪ 내가 왜 이럴까?
I've always longed for adventure
♪ 늘 못하던 걸
하고 싶은 모험심이
To do the things I've never dared
♪ 있었는데
용기를 내어 모험을
Now here I'm facing adventure
♪ 시작하려는 순간인데
Then why am I so scared?
♪ 왜 이리 두려울까?
A captain with seven children
♪ 대령과 일곱 명의 아이들
♪ 그게 뭐 대수라고
What's so fearsome about that?
I must stop these doubts
All these worries
♪ 이런 의심과 걱정을
멈추지 않으면
If I don't, I just know I'll turn back
♪ 다시 돌아가야 해
I must dream of the things
I am seeking
♪ 꿈 꿔 보는 거야
♪ 용기를 가지고
I am seeking the courage I lack
The courage to serve them
With reliance
♪ 믿음과 용기를 가지고
Face my mistakes without defiance
♪ 실수를 두려워하지 말고
Show them I'm worthy
♪ 내 가치를 알게 하고
And while I show them
♪ 날 보여주는 거야
I'll show me
♪ 바로 나 자신을
So let them bring on
All their problems
♪ 그래서 모든 것을
나와 의논하게 하고
I'll do better than my best
♪ 최선을 다해 잘 해 내야지
I have confidence
They'll put me to the test
♪ 날 시험해 보겠다면
But I'll make them see
I have confidence in me
♪ 내 자신감을 보여 줘야지
Somehow, I will impress them
♪ 난 그들에게 좋은 인상을
줄 거야
I will be firm but kind
♪ 확고하면서도 자상하게
And all those children
Heaven bless them
♪ 주님, 그 애들을 축복하소서
They will look up to me
And mind me
♪ 그들은 날 존경하며
따를 거 야
With each step, I am more certain
♪ 하나씩 분명히 해 가면
Everything will turn out fine
♪ 모든 일이 잘 될 거 야
I have confidence
The world can all be mine
♪ 세상이 내 것이 라는
They'll have to agree
I have confidence in me
♪ 자신감을 가져 야 해
I have confidence in sunshine
♪ 햇빛이 빛날 때도
I have confidence in rain
♪ 비가 올 때도
난 자신감이 있고
I have confidence
That spring will come again
♪ 봄이 다시 올 거라는
확신과 함께
Besides which you see
I have confidence in me
♪ 나 자신에 대한
자신감도 있어
Strength doesn't lie in numbers
♪ 사람이 많든
Strength doesn't lie in wealth
♪ 부유하든 상관없어
Strength lies in nights
Of peaceful slumbers
♪ 평화로운 안식을 얻은
이에게 찾아오지
When you wake up, wake up
It's healthy
♪ 어서 깨어라
All I trust I leave my heart to
♪ 믿는 모든 걸
마음에 담고
All I trust becomes my own
♪ 믿는 모든 걸
내 것으로 만들어
I have confidence in confidence alone
♪ 이제 나는 자신 있어
혼자서도
Oh, help.
세상에
I have confidence in confidence alone
♪ 이젠 혼자서도
자신이 있고
Besides which you see
I have confidence
♪ 나에 대한 확신도 있어
In me
♪ 나에게는
Hello. Here I am.
저 왔어요
I'm from the convent.
I'm the new governess, captain.
새 가정교사예요, 대령님
And I'm the old butler, fr?lein.
난 여기 집사요
Well, how do you do?
그래요, 안녕하세요?
You'll wait here, please.
여기서 기다리세요
In the future, remember certain rooms
in this house are not to be disturbed.
앞으론 제한된 곳에는
들어가면 안돼요
Yes, captain, sir.
네, 대령님
- Why do you stare at me that way?
- You don't look like a sea captain.
- 왜 그렇게 보는 거요?
- 해군 대령님같이 안보여서요
I'm afraid you don't look
very much like a governess.
당신도 가정교사 같진 않군
- Turn around.
- What?
- 한번 돌아봐요
- 네?
Turn.
돌아봐요
Hat off.
모자도 벗어봐요
Put on another dress
before meeting the children.
애들 보기 전에
다른 옷을 입어요
But I don't have another.
다른 옷이 없어요
When we enter the abbey,
our worldly clothes go to the poor.
수녀원에 들어갈 때
극빈자들에게 줬거든요
What about this one?
그 옷은?
The poor didn't want it.
이 옷은 안 받더군요
There wasn't time to make a new dress.
I can make clothes.
좋은 옷을 만들 수 있지만
시간이 없었죠
I'll see that you get some material.
가능하면 오늘 옷감을
Today, if possible.
주도록 하겠소
- Now, fr?lein...
- Maria.
- 이름이...
- 마리아예요
I don't know how much
the abbess told you.
원장이 얼마나 자세히
얘길 했는지는 몰라도
- Not much.
- You are the twelfth governess...
애들 엄마가 죽은 뒤로
...to look after my children
since their mother died.
당신이 12번째 가정교사요
I trust you will be an improvement
on the last one.
저 번 선생 보단 낫길 바래요
She stayed only two hours.
온 지 2시간 만에 나갔지
What's wrong with the children, sir?
애들에게 문제가 있나요?
Nothing is wrong with the children,
only the governesses.
애들 잘못은 없소
가정교사가 문제지
They could not maintain discipline,
without which the house cannot be run.
규율을 안 지키더군
규율 없인 안 된다는 걸 아시오
Drill them in their studies.
매일 아침 공부를 시키시오
I will not permit them to dream
away their summer holidays.
방학을 낭비해선 안되죠
Each afternoon,
they march, breathing deeply.
오후에는 행진을 하고
Bedtime is to be strictly observed.
취침시간을 엄수하시오
When do they play?
언제 놀게 하죠?
You will see to it that they conduct
themselves with the utmost decorum.
늘 단정하고 예의바른
모습들이어야 하오
- I am placing you in command.
- Yes, sir.
- 당신에게 애들 지휘를 맡기겠소
- 알겠습니다
Now...
새로 오신
...this is your new governess,
Fr?lein Maria.
마리아 선생님이시다
Give your name at your signal.
신호에 맞춰 이름을 대라
Fr?lein, listen carefully. Learn
their signals so you can call them.
선생은 신호를 잘 익히시오
Liesl.
리즐
Friedrich.
프레미드릭
Louisa.
루이자
Kurt.
커트
Brigitta.
브리지타
Marta.
마타
Gretl.
그래틀
Now, let's see how well you listened.
얼마나 잘 익혔나 봅시다
I won't need to whistle for them,
Reverend Captain.
그런 걸로 애들을
부를 순 없어요
I mean, I'll use their names.
Such lovely names.
애들의 사랑스러운
이름을 부르겠어요
Fr?lein, this is a large house.
The grounds are extensive.
이 집은 매우 넓고 큰데
And I will not have anyone shouting.
난 고함소리는 질색이오
You will take this, please.
Learn to use it.
이걸 갖고 익혀둬요
The children will help you.
애들이 도와 줄 거요
Now, when I want you,
this is what you will hear.
당신을 부를 땐
이렇게 하겠소
Oh, no, sir. I'm sorry, sir!
죄송하지만
I could never answer to a whistle.
그런 신호엔 대답 못해요
Whistles are for animals,
not for children.
동물에게나 하지
애들이나
And definitely not for me.
저에게는 하지 마세요
It would be too humiliating.
너무 모욕적이에요
Fr?lein, were you this much trouble
at the abbey?
수녀원에서도 문제를
일으킨 적이 있었소?
Oh, much more, sir.
아주 많죠
I don't know your signal.
실례지만 당신 신호를
몰라요
You may call me "captain."
그냥 대령이라 부르시오
At ease.
편히 쉬어요
Now that there's just us...
이제 우리끼리니까
...would you please tell me all your
names again and how old you are.
이름과 나이를
다시 말해줘요
I'm Liesl. I'm 16 years old,
and I don't need a governess.
리즐, 16살이고
가정교사는 필요 없어요
I'm glad you told me, Liesl.
We'll just be good friends.
말해 줘서 고마워
좋은 친구가 되자
I'm Friedrich. I'm 14.
I'm impossible.
프레미드릭, 14살이고
불가능한 애예요
Really? Who told you that, Friedrich?
그래? 누가 그랬지?
Fr?lein Josephine.
Four governesses ago.
네 번째 가정교사였던
죠세핀 선생님이오
I'm Brigitta.
브리지타예요
You didn't tell me how old you are,
Louisa.
나이는 말 안 했네,
루이자
I'm Brigitta. She's Louisa.
제가 브리지타고
루이자는
She's 13 years old, and you're smart.
13살이죠, 똑똑하시네요
I'm 10, and I think your dress
is the ugliest one I ever saw.
전 열 살이에요
옷이 보기 흉하시군요
- Brigitta, you shouldn't say that.
- Why not?
- 그런 말하면 실례야
- 왜?
- Don't you think it's ugly?
- Of course.
- 오빠는 그렇게 생각 안 해?
- 그렇지만
But Fr?lein Helga's was ugliest.
헐리 선생이 더 했어
I'm Kurt. I'm 11.
I'm incorrigible.
커트, 11살이고
구제불능이죠
- Congratulations.
- What's "incorrigible"?
- 축하한다
- "구제불능" 뜻을 아세요?
I think it means you want
to be treated like a boy.
소년답게 대우받고
싶다는 거지
I'm Marta, and I'm going to be
7 on Tuesday.
마타 예요
화요일이면 7살인데
I'd like a pink parasol.
분홍양산을 갖고 싶어요
Pink's my favorite color too.
분홍색은 나도 좋아한단다
Yes, you're Gretl.
넌 그래틀 이지
And you're 5 years old?
5살?
My, you're practically a lady.
숙녀가 다 됐는걸
I have to tell you a secret.
I've never been a governess.
비밀인데
난 가정교사는 처음이야
You don't know anything
about being a governess?
가정교사에 대해
아무 것도 모르세요?
Nothing. I'll need lots of advice.
몰라, 충고 좀 해 줘
The best way to start is to tell
Father to mind his own business.
아빠가 조언하면
참견 말라고 하세요
Never come to dinner on time.
식사 때는 늦게 오고
Never eat your soup quietly.
스프는 소리내서 먹고
During dessert,
always blow your nose.
후식 땐 코를 푸세요
Don't you believe a word they say,
Fr?lein Maria.
언니, 오빠들 말
믿지 마세요
- Oh, why not?
- Because I like you.
- 왜?
- 선생님이 좋으니까요
Children, outside for your walk.
얘들아, 산책할 시간이다
Father's orders. Hurry up.
아빠 명령이니
Quick, quick, quick.
서둘러라
Fr?lein Maria, I'm Frau Schmidt,
the housekeeper.
난 슈미트라고
이 집 가정부죠
How do you do.
안녕하세요
I'll show you to your room.
Follow me.
방을 안내하죠
따라오세요
Poor little dears.
가엾은 애들이에요
You're very lucky.
With Fr?lein Helga it was a snake.
운이 좋으시군요
헬가 선생님 때는 뱀이었죠
Good evening.
다들 모였군요
- Good evening, children.
- Good evening, Fr?lein Maria.
- 얘들아, 안녕?
- 어서 오세요, 마리아 선생님
Enchanting little ritual.
수녀원에서 익힌
Something you learned at the abbey?
매혹적인 의식인가요?
No.
아뇨
Rheumatism.
신경통 때문이죠
Excuse me, captain.
Haven't we forgotten to thank the Lord?
실례지만
식사 기도를 해야죠?
For what we receive,
may the Lord make us truly thankful.
일용할 음식을 주셔서
감사합니다
- Amen.
- 아멘
I'd like to thank you all...
아까 주머니에
...for the precious gift
you left in my pocket today.
좋은 선물을
넣어줘서 고마워요
What gift?
무슨 선물이죠?
It's a secret between
the children and me.
애들과 저만의
비밀이에요
Then I suggest you keep it,
and let us eat.
그러면 조용히
식사나 합시다
Knowing how nervous
I must have been...
낯선 나를 받아줄까 하고
...a stranger in a new household...
얼마나 불안했는지 몰라요
...knowing how important it was
for me to feel accepted...
제겐 아주 의미가 컸어요
...it was so kind and thoughtful of
you to make my first moments here...
날 따뜻하고 기쁘게
맞아 줘 고마웠어요
...so warm and happy...
따뜻하고 기쁘고
...and pleasant.
즐거웠어요
- What is the matter, Marta?
- Nothing.
- 왜 그러니, 마타야?
- 아니에요
Fr?lein...
마리아
...is it to be at every meal
or merely at dinnertime...
당신은 저녁 식사시간에
...that you intend leading us through
this rare and wonderful new world...
우리에게 소화불량을
안겨 주려고
...of indigestion?
작정을 했소?
They're all right, captain.
They're just happy.
행복해서 그런 거예요
- Rolfe, good evening.
- Good evening, Franz.
- 랄프, 어서 와라
- 안녕하세요
- I trust everything is under control?
- Yes, yes.
- 별일 없으시죠?
- 그래
- Are there any developments?
- Perhaps.
- 별 진전은 없나?
- 글쎄요
- Is the captain home?
- He's at dinner.
- 대령님 계신가요?
- 식사 중이시네
- With the family?
- Yes.
- 가족과요?
- 그래
Give him this telegram at once.
이 전보를 속히
전해 주세요
Certainly.
그러지
A telegram for you, sir.
전보입니다
Franz? Who delivered it?
누가 배달 왔어요?
That young lad Rolfe, of course.
물론, 랄프죠
Father, may I be excused?
그만 일어나도 돼요?
Children, in the morning
I shall be going to Vienna.
얘들아, 난 내일 아침
비엔나에 가봐야겠다
Not again, Father!
또요?
How long will you be gone this time?
얼마나 있다 오세요?
I'm not sure, Gretl.
잘 모르겠구나
- To visit Baroness Schraeder again?
- Mind your own business!
- 또 슈나이더 부인을 만나러요?
- 상관할 일이 아냐
As a matter of fact, yes, Louisa.
사실은 그렇단다
- Why can't we ever see the baroness?
- Why would she want to see you?
- 저희는 언제 만나보죠?
- 네가 왜 만나니?
You are going to see the baroness.
I'm bringing her back with me to visit.
이번엔 아줌마와 함께
집에 오도록 하마
And Uncle Max.
맥스 아저씨도
Uncle Max!
아저씨도요?
Rolfe!
랄프!
Oh, Rolfe!
- No, Liesl. We mustn't!
- Why not, silly?
- 이러면 안돼!
- 왜? 바보같이
- I don't know--
- Isn't this why you're waiting?
- 글쎄, 어쨌든-
- 이걸 위해 기다린 거잖아?
Yes, of course.
물론이지
- I've missed you, Liesl.
- You have? How much?
- 보고 싶었어
- 정말? 얼마나?
I even thought of sending a telegram,
so I'd be able to deliver it here.
내가 직접 전보를 쳐서
가져올 정도로
Oh, that's a lovely thought!
Why don't you, right now?
그런 생각까지 하다니!
그럼 당장 해보지 그래?
- But I'm here!
- Please, Rolfe. Send me a telegram.
- 여기 왔잖아!
- 나한테 전보를 쳐 봐
I'll start it for you.
"Dear Liesl..."
시작은 내가 할게
"사랑하는 리즐에게"
"Dear Liesl: I'd like to be able
to tell you...
"사랑하는 리즐,
너에 대한"
...how I feel about you. Stop.
"감정을 말해주고 싶어, 이만"
Unfortunately, this wire
is already too expensive.
"전보 값이 너무 올라갔어"
Sincerely, Rolfe."
"충심으로, 랄프가"
- "Sincerely"?
- Cordially.
- "충심으로"?
- 진심으로
- "Cordially"?
- Affectionately?
- "진심으로"?
- 사랑하는?
Will there be any reply?
답장이 있어야지?
"Dear Rolfe: Stop.
"사랑하는 랄프, 이만"
Don't stop! Your Liesl."
"아니, 계속해! 너의 리즐"
If only we didn't have to wait
for someone to send Father a telegram.
누군가 아빠에게 전보를
쳐야 네가 올 텐데
How do I know when I'll see you again?
다음엔 언제 만나지?
Well, let's see...
글쎄
I could come here by mistake.
다른 걸 가져올까?
With a telegram for Colonel Schneider!
He's here from Berlin staying with--
슈나이더 대령의 전보 말야
그는 지금 여기에 있거든...
No one knows he's here.
Don't tell your father.
이 사실은 아무도 몰라
아버지께도 말하지마
- Why not?
- Your father's so Austrian.
- 왜?
- 지나치게 오스트리아 식이니까
We're all Austrian.
우린 오스트리아인 이잖아
Some think we ought to be German, and
they're very mad at those who don't.
이젠 독일인이 돼야 해
안 그러면 좋지 않아
They're getting ready to--
단지 대령님께...
Let's hope your father
doesn't get into trouble.
아무 일 없길 바래서야
Don't worry. He's a big naval hero.
He was even decorated by the emperor.
걱정 마, 해군 영웅이셨고
황제께 훈장도 받으셨어
I don't worry about him.
I worry about his daughter.
알아, 대령님이 아니고
네가 걱정돼서 그래
- Me? Why?
- Well, you're so--
내가? 왜?
- ♪ 너는
- ♪ 뭐가?
♪ 너무 어리다고
- You're such a baby!
- I'm 16. What's such a baby about that?
♪ 16살인데 너무 어리다니?
You wait, little girl
On an empty stage
♪ 꼬마 아가씨,
인생의 무대 위에
For fate to turn the light on
♪ 운명의 불이 켜질 시기예요
Your life, little girl
Is an empty page
♪ 네게도 남자가
That men will want to write on
♪ 나타날 때가 된 거야
To write on
♪ 남자가 나타나?
You are 16 going on 17
♪ 16살에서 17살이 되니
Baby, it's time to think
♪ 생각할 시기인 거야
Better beware
Be canny and careful
♪ 심사숙고해야 해
Baby, you're on the brink
♪ 벼랑 끝에 선 듯
위험하지만
You are 16 going on 17
♪ 16살에서 17살이 되면
Fellows will fall in line
♪ 남자들이 줄을 설 거야
Eager young lads
And rou? and cads
♪ 정열적인 청년과
난봉꾼들이
Will offer you food and wine
♪ 술을 권할 테지
Totally unprepared are you
♪ 넌 세상 남자들과
To face a world of men
♪ 만날 준비가 안됐어
Timid and shy and scared are you
♪ 네 시야 밖의 것에는
Of things beyond your ken
♪ 소심하고 두려워하니
You need someone older and wiser
♪ 너를 가르쳐 줄
Telling you what to do
♪ 현명한 어른이 필요하지
I am 17 going on 18
♪ 난 17살에서 18살이 되니
I'll take care of you
♪ 내가 널 돌봐 줄 거야
I am 16 going on 17
♪ 16살에서 17살이 되는
I know that I'm naive
♪ 순진한 나를 알아요
Fellows I meet
May tell me I'm sweet
♪ 남자가 날 좋아한다고 하면
And willingly I believe
♪ 그대로 믿어버리죠
I am 16 going on 17
♪ 16살에서 17살이 되는
♪ 난 장미처럼 순결해요
Innocent as a rose
Bachelor dandies
Drinkers of brandies
♪ 브랜디를 마시는
신사에 대해
What do I know of those?
♪ 내가 뭘 알겠어요?
Totally unprepared am I
♪ 난 세상의 남자들과
To face a world of men
♪ 만날 준비가 안됐어요
Timid and shy and scared am I
♪ 내 시야 밖의 것에는
Of things beyond my ken
♪ 소심하고 두려워하니
I need someone older and wiser
♪ 나를 가르쳐 줄
Telling me what to do
♪ 현명한 어른이 필요해요
You are 17 going on 18
♪ 당신은 이제 18살이 되니
I'll depend on you
♪ 당신에게 의지할게요
Come in.
들어오세요
Frau Schmidt.
슈미트 부인!
For your new dresses.
대령님이 마을에서
- The captain had these sent from town.
- Oh, how lovely!
- 새 옷감을 주문해 주셨어요
- 아주 곱군요!
These will make the prettiest
clothes I've ever had.
예쁜 옷을 만들어 볼게요
Do you think he would
get me more material if I asked?
옷감을 더 달라고 하면
주실까요?
- How many dresses do you need?
- Not for me, for the children.
- 몇 벌이나 필요하신데요?
- 제 것이 아니고 애들 거요
I want to make them
some play clothes.
놀이 옷을 만들 거예요
The von Trapp children don't play.
They march.
애들은 놀지 않고
행진을 해요
Surely you don't approve of that.
그걸 찬성하는 건
아니겠죠?
Ever since the captain
lost his poor wife...
대령님은 아내를 잃은 후
...he runs this house as if on
one of his ships.
모든 게 군대식이에요
Whistles, orders.
호루라기와 규율이
No more music, no more laughing.
음악과 웃음을 대신하고
Nothing that reminds him of her.
Even the children.
아내를 생각나게 하는 건
모두 금지예요, 애들도요
But that's so wrong.
그래선 안돼요
Oh, well.
그렇지만
How do you like your room?
There'll be new drapes at the windows.
방은 어때요?
새 커튼을 달아줄게요
But these are fine.
새 커튼? 저것도 좋아요
New ones have been ordered.
어쨌든 이미 주문했어요
- But I really don't need them.
- Good night, now.
- 필요 없는데요
- 잘 자요
Frau Schmidt, if I asked the captain
tomorrow about the material...?
부인, 대령님께
옷감 얘길 해 보세요
- He's leaving in the morning.
- Of course. How long will he be gone?
- 내일 아침 비엔나에 가세요
- 그렇군요, 얼마동안 가 계시죠?
It depends. The last time he visited
the baroness, he stayed for a month.
모르죠, 지난번엔 한 달간
머물렀어요
I shouldn't be saying this to you.
I don't know you that well.
당신을 잘 모르면서
이런 말하면 안되지만
But if you ask me,
the captain's thinking seriously...
여름에 그녀와 결혼식을
...of marrying her before
summer's over.
올릴 모양이에요
Wonderful! The children will
have a mother again.
정말 잘됐군요
새 엄마가 생기니까요
Yes.
그래요
Well, good night.
잘 자요
Good night.
안녕히 주무세요
주님, 왜 보내셔는지
알겠어요
Dear Father, now I know
why you sent me here.
새 엄마를 맞게
도와주란 거죠?
To help these children
prepare for a new mother.
행복한 가정이 되게
해주세요
And I pray this will become
a happy family in thy sight.
대령님과 리즐, 프레드릭,
God bless the captain.
God bless Liesl and Friedrich.
루이자, 브리지타,
마타, 그레틀
God bless Louisa, Brigitta,
Marta and little Gretl.
그리고 누구더라, 이름이...
And I forgot the other boy.
What's his name?
그 애를 위해 축복해 주세요
Well, God bless what's-his-name.
원장 수녀님과 마가렛도
God bless the Reverend Mother
and Sister Margaretta...
다른 모든 수녀님께도
...and everybody at the abbey.
그리고 리즐 말인데요
And now, dear God, about Liesl.
리즐과도 친구가
Help her know that I'm her friend...
될 수 있게 도와주세요
...and help her tell me
what she's been up to.
아빠에게 말할 건가요?
Are you going to tell on me?
이해로 인도하게
도와주십시오
Help me to be understanding
so I may guide her footsteps.
성부, 성자, 성신의
이름으로 아멘
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
산책하고 와보니
문이 잠겼는데
I was out walking and somebody
locked the doors early.
사람을 깨우긴 싫고
창문이 열려 있어서...
I didn't want to wake everybody,
so when I saw your window open...
아빠에게 말 안 할거죠?
You're not going to tell Father,
are you?
어떻게 올라왔지?
How did you climb up?
가정교사를 놀려 줄 때
올라오곤 했어요
It's how we always got in
to play tricks on the governess.
루이자는 거미를
갖고도 올라와요
Louisa can make it with
a whole jar of spiders in her hand.
거미라고?
Spiders?
Liesl, were you out walking
all by yourself?
여태 혼자 있었던 거니?
지금 옷을 빨면
아무도 눈치 못 챌 거야
If we wash that dress tonight,
nobody would notice it tomorrow.
이 옷을 입어라
You could put this on.
벗은 옷을 빨래 통에 넣고
Take your dress and put it
to soak in the bathtub.
다시 와서 얘기하자
Come back here and sit on the bed,
and we'll have a talk.
가정교사가 필요
없다고 했었지만
I told you today
I didn't need a governess.
필요한 거 같아요
Well, maybe I do.
그레틀, 무섭니?
Gretl, are you scared?
천둥소리가 무서워?
You're not frightened
of a storm, are you?
나와 같이 있자
You just stay right here with me.
- 다른 얘들은?
- 자요, 무서워하지도 않고
- Where are the others?
- They're asleep. They're not scared.
자, 봐라
Oh, no? Look.
모두 침대위로 올라오렴
All right, up here on the bed.
- 정말요?
- 이번 한번 만이다
- Really?
- Well, just this once. Come on.
- 남자들만 기다리면 돼
- 안 올 거예요, 용감하거든요
- Now we'll wait for the boys.
- You won't see them. Boys are brave.
무서워서 온 건 아니겠지?
You weren't scared, were you?
아뇨, 잘 계신가
확인하러 왔어요
Oh, no. We just wanted
to be sure that you weren't.
- 아주 고맙구나
- 제 생각이 아니라
- That's very thoughtful of you.
- It wasn't my idea.
커트의 생각이었죠
It was Kurt's!
맞아, 커트였어!
커트에게 축복을
Kurt! That's the one I left out!
God bless Kurt.
왜 천둥이 치죠?
Why does it do that?
번개가 천둥에게 물으면
대답하느라고
The lightning talks to the thunder,
and the thunder answers.
- 번개가 못되게 굴었나 봐요
- 글쎄
- But lightning must be nasty.
- Not really.
천둥이 왜 화났죠?
Why does the thunder get so angry?
난 울 뻔했어요
It makes me want to cry.
난 기분이 나쁠 땐
좋은 일만 생각한단다
Whenever I'm feeling unhappy,
I just try to think of nice things.
어떤 거요?
What kind of things?
좋은 것들이지
Well, let me see. Nice things...
수선화
Daffodils.
푸른 초원
Green meadows.
하늘의 별들
Skies full of stars.
장미 꽃잎의 빗방울과
아기 고양이의 수염
Raindrops on roses
And whiskers on kittens
주전자와 예쁜 장갑
Bright copper kettles
And warm woolen mittens
잘 포장된 소포
꾸러미들
Brown paper packages
Tied up with strings
이건 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
♪ 크림색 조랑말과
사과 과자
Cream-colored ponies
And crisp apple strudels
♪ 초인종과 썰매 방울
Doorbells and sleigh bells
And schnitzel with noodles
♪ 달보고 날갯짓하는 거위
Wild geese that fly
With the moon on their wings
♪ 이게 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
♪ 청색 띠의 하얀 옷의
소녀들
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
♪ 코와 눈썹에 떨어진
눈송이들
Snowflakes that stay
On my nose and eyelashes
♪ 봄기운에 녹는 은빛
겨울풍경
Silver white winters
That melt into springs
♪ 이게 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
♪ 개에 물리고
When the dog bites
♪ 벌에 쏘이고
When the bee stings
♪ 마음이 슬플 때도
When I'm feeling sad
♪ 좋은 것들만 생각한다면
I simply remember my favorite things
♪ 즐거워질 수 있어
And then I don't feel so bad
- 정말이에요?
- 물론, 해봐
- Does it work?
- Of course.
- 좋아하는 게 뭐지?
- 갯버들!
- What do you like?
- Pussy willow!
- 크리스마스!
- 어린 토끼들!
- Christmas!
- Bunny rabbits!
뱀!
Snakes!
- 초코렛 아이스크림!
- 방학!
- Chocolate icing!
- No school!
베개싸움!
Pillow fights!
- 전보!
- 생일선물!
- Telegrams!
- Birthday presents!
- 아무 선물이나!
- 무당벌레!
- Any presents!
- Ladybugs!
시원한 재채기!
A good sneeze!
축복이 있길!
Gesundheit!
정말 재밌지?
See what fun it is?
♪ 청색 띠의 하얀 옷의
소녀들
Raindrops on roses
And whiskers on kittens
♪ 코와 눈썹에 떨어진
눈송이들
Bright copper kettles
And warm woolen mittens
♪ 봄기운에 녹는
은빛 겨울풍경
Brown paper packages
Tied up with strings
♪ 이게 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
♪ 크림색 조랑말과
사과 과자
Cream-colored ponies
And crisp apple strudels
♪ 초인종과 썰매 방울
Doorbells and sleigh bells
And schnitzel with noodles
달보고 날갯짓하는 거위
Wild geese that fly
With the moon on their wings
♪ 이게 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
다함께
Together.
♪ 청색 띠의 하얀 옷의
소녀들
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
♪ 코와 눈썹에 떨어진
눈송이들
Snowflakes that stay
On my nose and eyelashes
♪ 봄기운에 녹는 은빛
겨울풍경
Silver white winters
That melt into springs
♪ 이게 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
♪ 개에 물리고...
When the dog bi--
Dog bites.
어서 오세요
Hello.
마리아양, 취침시간을
엄수하라고 했잖소?
Fr?lein, did I not tell you that
bedtime is to be strictly observed?
천둥 때문에 달래느라고...
The children were upset
by the storm, so I--
그랬어요
You did, sir.
그런 간단한 규칙도
제대로 기억 못하오?
Do you, or do you not, have difficulty
remembering such simple instructions?
천둥이 칠 때만요
Only during thunderstorms.
리즐?
- Liesl?
- Yes, Father?
식사 후에 보이지 않던데?
I don't recall seeing you
after dinner.
그래요? 사실은-
Really? As a matter of fact--
그래서?
Yes?
그러니까-
Well, I was--
식사 후 저와 함께
What she would like to say...
저녁 내내 얘길 나눴어요
...is that she and I have
been getting acquainted tonight.
어쨌든, 너무 늦었으니
가서 자도록 해
It's too late to go into that. You
heard your father. Go back to bed.
선생
Fr?lein...
알다시피
난 내일 떠납니다
...you have managed to remember
I'm leaving in the morning?
이 집에서 제일 중요한 건
규율이란 걸 명심하시오
Is it also possible you remember the
first rule in this house is discipline?
내가 없는 동안
Then I trust that before I return...
익히도록 하시오
...you'll have acquired some?
대령님?
Captain?
떠나시기 전에 애들 옷감을
주셨으면 해요
Could I talk to you about clothes
for the children for when they play?
- 놀이 옷을 만들 거예요
- 당신은 정말이지
- If I could have some material.
- You are many things.
일을 번거롭게 만드는군
Not the least of which is repetitious.
- 애들이에요!
- 맞소
- But they're children!
- Yes.
난 아버지고요
And I'm their father.
잘 자요
Good night.
♪ 청색 띠의 하얀 옷의
소녀들
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
♪ 개에 물리고
벌에 쏘이고
When the dog bites
When the bee stings
♪ 마음이 슬플 때
When I'm feeling sad
♪ 좋은 것들만 생각한다면
I simply remember my favorite things
♪ 즐거워 질 수
And then I don't feel
♪ 있겠지
So bad
저길 봐라!
Children, over here. See!
가자
Come on.
선생님?
Fr?lein Maria?
매일 이렇게 놀아도 돼요?
Can we do this every day?
- 매일 놀면 싫증날텐데
- 그렇겠군요
- Don't you think you'd get tired of it?
- I suppose so.
하루씩 걸러서는요?
Every other day?
지난 번 선생님 칫솔에 접착제
붙여 본 뒤로 제일 즐거워
I haven't had so much fun since we put
glue on Fr?lein Josephine's toothbrush.
너희 같이 착한 애들이
그런 장난을 하다니...
I can't understand how children
as nice as you can play such tricks.
- 간단해요
- 왜 그랬지?
- It's easy.
- But why do it?
그래야 아빠의 관심을 끌죠
How else can we get
Father's attention?
그랬구나
Oh, I see.
생각 좀 해봐야겠구나
We'll have to think about that one.
자, 이제 모여봐라
All right, over here.
뭘 할 건데요?
What are we going to do?
슈나이더 부인이 오면
부를 노래연습
Think of a song for the baroness.
아빠는 노래를 싫어해요
Father doesn't like us to sing.
마음을 바꿀 수 있어
무슨 노래를 알지?
Perhaps we can change his mind.
Now, what songs do you know?
아는 노래가 없어요
We don't know any songs.
- 전혀?
- 부를 줄도 몰라요
- Not any?
- We don't even know how to sing.
그럼, 배워야 되겠군
Let's not lose time. You must learn.
어떻게요?
But how?
♪ 기초부터 시작하자
Let's start at the very beginning
♪ 배우기 쉬운 노래가 있어
A very good place to start
♪ 글을 읽을 땐
뭐부터 배우지?
When you read you begin with
♪ A, B, C
A, B, C
♪ 노래를 배울 땐,
도, 레, 미
When you sing, you begin with
Do-re-mi
♪ 도-레-미
♪ 이게 처음 시작하는
3개의 음이란다
The first three notes
Just happen to be
♪ 도-레-미
Do-re-mi
♪ 도- 레- 미- 파- 솔- 라- 시
Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti
좀더 쉽 게 해보자
Let's see if I can make it easier.
♪ "도"는 사슴 중에서도 암 사슴
"Doe," a deer
A female deer
♪ "레"는 금색 태양 빛
"Ray," a drop of golden sun
♪ "미"는 날 부르는 이름
"Me," a name I call myself
♪ "파"는 멀리 멀리 가는 것
"Far," a long, long way to run
♪ "솔"은 꿰매는 바늘
"Sew," a needle pulling thread
♪ "라"는 솔 다음에 오는 음
"La," a note to follow sew
♪ "시"는 빵과 마시는 차
"Tea," a drink with jam and bread
♪ 그럼 다시 돌아가서, 도
That will bring us back to doe
Oh, oh, oh
- ♪ 도!
- ♪ 사슴 중에서도 암사슴
- Doe!
- A deer, a female deer
- ♪ 레!
- ♪ 금속 태양 빛
- Ray!
- A drop of golden sun
- ♪ 미!
- ♪ 날 부르는 이름
- Me!
- A name I call myself
- ♪ 파!
- ♪ 멀리 멀리 가는 것
- Far!
- A long, long way to run
♪ 솔은 꿰매는 바늘
Sew, a needle pulling thread
- ♪ 라
- ♪ 솔 다음에 오는 음
- La!
- A note to follow sew
- ♪ 시
- ♪ 시는 빵과 마시는 차
- Tea
- A drink with jam and bread
♪ 그럼 다시 돌아가서
That will bring us back to
- ♪ 도!
- ♪ 도는 사슴 중에서도 암사슴
- Doe
- A deer, a female deer
♪ 레는 금색 태양 빛
Ray, a drop of golden sun
♪ 미는 날 부르는 이름
Me, a name I call myself
♪ 파는 멀리 멀리 가는 것
Far, a long, long way to run
♪ 솔은 꿰매는 바늘
Sew, a needle pulling thread
♪ 라는 솔 다음에 오는 음
La, a note to follow sew
♪ 시는 빵과 마시는 차
Tea, a drink with jam and bread
♪ 그럼 다시 돌아가서, 도
That will bring us back to doe
♪ 도-레-미-파-솔-라-시-도-솔-도
Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do, so-do
♪ 도레미는 노래를 만드는
도구일 뿐이야
Do-re-mi-fa-so and so on are only
the tools we use to build a song.
그것만 알면
다른 많은 노래를
Once you have them in your head
you can sing different tunes...
부를 수 있지, 봐라
...by mixing them up. Like this:
♪ 솔-도-라-파-미-도-레
So-do-la-fa-mi-do-re
해 보렴
Can you do that?
♪ 솔-도-라-파-미-도-레
So-do-la-fa-mi-do-re
♪ 솔-도-라-시-도-레-도
So-do-la-ti-do-re-do
그 럼 합쳐서 불러보자
Now, put it all together.
♪ 솔-도-라-파-미-도-레
So-do-la-fa-mi-do-re
♪ 솔-도-라-시-도-레-도
So-do-la-ti-do-re-do
- 잘했다
- 하지만 뜻이 없잖아요
- Good.
- But it doesn't mean anything.
각 음에다 말을 넣으면
되는 거야
So we put in words.
One word for every note.
이렇게
Like this:
♪ 노래 할 음표만
알고 있다면
When you know the notes to sing
어떤 노래라도
부를 수 있어요
You can sing most anything
다같이!
Together!
♪ 노래할 음표만
알고 있다면
When you know the notes to sing
♪ 어떤 노 래라도
부를 수 있어요
You can sing most anything
- ♪ 도
- ♪ 사슴 중에서도 암사슴
- Doe
- A deer, a female deer
- ♪ 레
- ♪ 금색 태양 빛
- Ray
- A drop of golden sun
- ♪ 미
- ♪ 날부르는 소리
- Me
- A name I call myself
- ♪ 파
- ♪ 멀리 멀리 가는 것
- Far
- A long long way to run
- ♪ 솔
- ♪ 꿰매는 바늘
- Sew
- A needle pulling thread
- ♪ 라
- ♪ 솔 다음에 오는 음
- La
- A note to follow sew
- ♪ 시
- ♪ 빵과 마시는 차
- Tea
- A drink with jam and bread
♪ 그럼 다시 돌아가서, 도
That will bring us back to doe
- Do
- Re
- Mi
- Fa
- So
- La
- Ti
- Do, do
- La
- So
- Fa
- Mi
- Re
- Do
- Mi, mi
- Mi
- So, so
- Re
- Fa, fa
- La
- Ti, ti
- Do
- Mi, mi
- Mi
- So, so
- Re
- Fa, fa
- La
- Ti, ti
♪ 노래 할 음표만
알고 있다면
When you know the notes to sing
♪ 어떤 노래라도
부를 수 있어요
You can sing most anything
♪ 도
사슴 중에서도 암사슴
Doe!
A deer, a female deer
♪ 레
금빛 태양 빛
Ray!
A drop of golden sun
♪ 미
날 부르는 소리
Me!
A name I call myself
♪ 파
멀리 멀리 가는 것
Far!
A long long way to run
♪ 솔
꿰매는 바늘
Sew!
A needle pulling thread
♪ 라
솔 다음에 오는 음
La!
A note to follow sew
♪ 시
빵과 마시는 차
Tea!
A drink with jam and bread
♪ 그럼 다시 돌아가서
That will bring us back to
♪ 솔-도-라-파-미-도-레
So-do-la-fa-mi-do-re
So-do-la-fa-ti
♪ 솔-도-라-파-시
♪ 라-솔
La-so
Fa
Mi-re
♪ 시-도
Ti-do
♪ 솔-도
So-do!
저 산들 좀 봐요
너무나 웅장해요
The mountains are magnificent,
really magnificent.
- 당신을 위해 갖다놨지
- 그래요?
- I had them put up just for you.
- Oh?
높이가 3천 미터라도
Even if it's to a height
of 10,000 feet...
올라 갈 순 있어
...Georg always believes in
"rising to the occasion."
농담을 제대로 안 하면
초대 는 취소야
Unless the jokes improve,
I'm taking back my invitation.
자네가 초대했나?
내가 스스로 온 거지
You didn't invite me.
I invited myself.
- 맞아요
- 자넨 친구가 필요했고
- Naturally.
- You needed a chaperone...
난 요리가 있는 곳이
필요했지
...and I needed a place
where the cuisine is superb...
포도주도 있으면 좋고
...the wine cellar unexcelled...
아주비 싼 걸로
...and the price perfect.
맥스, 당신은 터무니 없어요
Max, you are outrageous.
난 매력적인 식객이야
Not at all.
I'm a very charming sponge.
들어 봐
Listen.
클롭만 성가대일세
That's the Klopmann Monastery Choir.
잘 하는데
They're good.
아주 잘해
Very good.
며칠간 구석구석
뒤져야겠어
I must explore this area
in the next few days.
배고픈 무명 합창대가
날 기다릴걸
Somewhere, a hungry singing group
is waiting for Max Detweiler...
짤즈부르크 대회를 위해서
...to pluck it out and make it famous
at the Salzburg Folk Festival.
- 명성을 주고 돈을 벌겠군
- 공평치 못해
- They get fame, you get money.
- It's unfair, I admit it.
언젠가는 바뀌어야 해
나도 명성을 얻을 거야
But someday that'll be changed.
I shall get the fame too.
저게 도대체 뭐죠?
Good heavens, what's this?
시골 개구쟁이들이오
It's nothing.
Just some local urchins.
당신과 여기 있으니
흥분돼요
This really is exciting for me, Georg.
Being here with you.
나무, 산, 호수
낯익은 것들인데?
Trees, lakes,
you've seen them before.
그런 뜻이 아닌 걸
알잖아요
That is not what I mean,
and you know it.
- 내 얘긴가? 나도 흥분돼
- 불가능한 일인가요?
- You mean me? I'm exciting?
- Is that so impossible?
글쎄, 경우에 따라서는
No, just highly improbable.
- 또 자기비하를 시작했군요
- 난 위험한 운전사라고
- There you go, running yourself down.
- Well, I'm a dangerous driver.
여기 있으니 당신 베일이
벗겨진 듯 해요
You're much less of a riddle
when I see you here, Georg.
- 내가 사는 곳이라서?
- 맞아요
- In my natural habitat?
- Yes, exactly.
내게 이곳이
어울린다는 건가?
Are you saying that I'm more
at home...
나무들 사이로 부는
바람과
...among the birds and the flowers
and the wind that moves...
꽃들이 있는 곳이?
...through the trees
like a restless sea?
시적이군요
How poetic.
그랬었나?
Yes, it was rather, wasn't it?
샹들리에가 있는
비엔나보다 낫다고?
More at home here than in Vienna
in all your glittering salons...
잡담과 샴페인에 빠져서
정신도 못 차리고
...gossiping gaily with bores I detest,
soaking myself in champagne...
누구의 곡인지도 모르면서
왈츠를 추는 곳보다
...stumbling about to waltzes
by Strausses I can't even remember?
- 낫다는 얘긴가?
- 네
- Is that what you're saying?
- Yes.
왜 그런 생각을 했지?
Now whatever gave you that idea?
여긴 정말 평화롭고
아름다운 곳이에요
Oh, I do like it here, Georg.
It's so lovely and peaceful.
어떻게 이런 곳을
자주 비웠죠?
How can you leave it so often?
살아가기 위한 활동을
해야했기 때문이지
Oh, pretending to be madly active,
I suppose.
목적도 있었고
Activity suggests a life
filled with purpose.
추억에서 도망친 건
아니고요?
Could it be running away
from memories?
일부러 이유를
만든 건지 모르지
Or perhaps just searching
for a reason to stay.
그래서 비엔나에 왔군요?
I hope that's why you've been
coming to Vienna so often.
- 아니면 누가 홀렸던가?
- 당신을 그렇게 말할 순 없지
- Were there other distractions?
- I'd hardly call you a distraction.
그럼, 어떻게 말할 거죠?
Well, what would you call me, Georg?
사랑스럽고
Lovely...
매혹적이고 위트에
우아함을 갖춘 여주인
...charming, witty, graceful,
the perfect hostess...
그리고 또한
...and, you're going to hate me
for this...
나의 구세주라고 할까
...in a way, my savior.
그건 로맨틱하지 않네요
Oh, how unromantic.
당신이 날 다시 세상에
I'd be an ungrateful wretch
if I didn't say...
돌려 보내줬다고
할 수 있지
...that you brought some meaning back
into my life.
놀랍군요
I am amusing, I suppose.
비엔나엔 좋은 재단사와
사교계 친구들도 있고
I have the finest couturier in Vienna
and a glittering circle of friends.
- 매일 파티를 열 수도 있죠
- 그래요
- I do give some rather gay parties.
- Oh, yes.
난 가진 게
But take all that away...
돈 뿐이었고 방황하고
있었어요
...and you have just wealthy,
unattached little me...
당신을 만나기 전
까지는요
...searching, just like you.
과자 더 드시겠어요?
More strudel, Herr Detweiler?
- 지금까지 몇 개 먹었지?
- 두 개요
- How many have I had?
- Two.
세 개 채우지
Make it an uneven three.
또 먹는군
욕구 불만이라도 있나?
Still eating, Max?
Must be unhappy.
휴록에게 쓸만한
중창단이 있더군
That mixed quartet I've been trying
to steal away from Sol Hurok.
- 어떻게 됐는데요?
- 어제 사스카가 뺏어갔어
- What happened?
- Sascha Petrie stole them first.
이건 도둑질이야
I hate thieves.
자신부터 좀 사랑하라고
Max, you really must try
and learn to love yourself.
파리, 로마, 스톡홀름에
전화했어
I had to call Paris, Rome
and Stockholm.
- 게일의 전화로요?
- 그럼, 어떻게 해?
- On Georg's telephone, of course.
- How else could I afford it?
난 부자가 좋아
그들과 함께 할 때의 내 삶도
I like rich people, the way they live
and how I live when I'm with them.
애들은 어딨지?
I wonder where the children are.
내가 온 걸 알고 숨었겠죠
They must have heard
I was coming and hid.
당신을 환영하길 바랬는데
I was hoping they'd be here
to welcome you.
맥스, 이젠 그만하고
기분을 풀게
Max, do step out of character for
a moment and try and be charming.
그럼
Well?
뭘 말이에요?
Well what?
결정 안 했나?
결혼 종소리가 나는건가?
Have you made up his mind?
Do I hear wedding bells?
- 아주 웅장하게요
- 잘됐군
- Pealing madly.
- Marvelous.
- 나라고는 말 안 했어요
- 무슨 소리요?
- Not necessarily for me.
- What kind of talk's that?
상관할 것 없잖아요
None-of-your-business talk.
우리 갖고 장난치지
마세요
I'm terribly fond of him,
so don't toy with us.
난 아이라서 장난이 좋으니
얘기해봐요
But I'm a child. I like toys.
So tell me everything.
어서, 적나라하게
구체적인 것까지
Come on. Tell me every teensy-weensy,
intimate, disgusting detail.
여기 데려온 건 결혼할
마음이 있다는 거겠죠?
Well, let's just say I have a feeling
I may be here on approval.
- 그럼, 당연하잖아
- 그렇게 쉽게?
- I approve of that. How can you miss?
- Far too easily.
하려면 할 수 있지
방법이 있을 거야
If I know you, darling,
and I do, you will find a way.
- 그는 평범하지 않아요
- 부유하지
- He's no ordinary man.
- No, he's rich.
죽은 아내의 상처가
깊어요
His wife's death gave him
a great heartache.
당신 남편은 재산을
남겼고
And your husband's death
gave you a great fortune.
맥스, 너무해요
Oh, Max, you really are a beast.
우린 가족 같잖아
둘이 잘되길 바란다고
You and Georg are like family.
That's why I want to see you married.
많은 돈이 한 집에
몰리겠군
We must keep all that lovely money
in the family.
- 뭘 하는 건가?
- 대령님
- What are you doing there?
- Oh, Captain von Trapp.
뭘 찾고 있었어요
I was just looking for...
그러니까 계신 줄
모르고...
I didn't see, I mean,
I didn't know you were--
히틀러 만세!
Heil Hitler!
넌 누구냐?
Who are you?
뎃웨일러씨의
전보입니다
I have a telegram for Herr Detweiler.
- 난데
- 네
- I am Herr Detweiler.
- Yes, sir.
배달이 끝났으면
어서 가!
You've delivered your telegram.
Now get out.
- 어린애잖아요
- 난 오스트리아 인이야
- Georg, he's just a boy.
- Yes, and I'm just an Austrian.
어차피 일어날 일이야
몸조심이나 해
Things will happen.
Make sure they don't happen to you.
그 따위 말 다신 하지마!
Max! Don't you ever say that again.
난 정치적 신념이 없어
I have no political convictions.
- 내가 뭘 어쩌겠나?
- 자넨 할 수 있어
- Can I help it if other people do?
- You can help it.
자네도 도와야 해
You must help it.
이봐요?
Hello?
멀리 갔군요, 어딨죠?
You're far away. Where are you?
모든 게 사라지고 있어
두려워
In a world that's disappearing,
I'm afraid.
내게 오게 할 방법은
없나요?
Is there any way I could bring you
back to the world I'm in?
- 아빠,
- 아빠다!
- Father! Father!
- There's your father!
대령님, 돌아오셨군요
Oh, captain, you're home!
당장 물에서 나오지 못해!
Come out of that water at once!
슈나이더 부인이군요?
Oh, you must be Baroness Schraeder.
물에 흠뻑 젖었어!
I'm soaked to the skin!
어서 줄 서!
Straight line!
슈나이더 부인이시다
This is Baroness Schraeder.
그리고
And these...
내 아이들이오
...are my children.
반가워요
How do you do?
어서 옷 갈아입고
다시 정렬해라, 당장!
Go inside, dry off, clean up, change
your clothes and report back here!
선생은 잠깐 봅시다
Fr?lein, you will stay here, please!
맥스에게 잠깐 가 볼게요
I think I'd better go see
what Max is up to.
자, 선생
Now, fr?lein...
정직한 대답을 원하오
...I want a truthful answer.
물론이죠
Yes, captain.
내 상상이 맞나요?
Is it possible,
or could I have just imagined it?
내 애들이 혹시 나무에
올라간 적 있소?
Have my children, by any chance,
been climbing trees today?
네
Yes, captain.
그럼
I see.
이건 어디서 난 거요?
And where, may I ask,
did they get these...?
- 놀이 옷 말인가요?
- 그렇게 부르는군
- Play clothes.
- Is that what they are?
제가 만들었어요
제 방 커튼으로요
I made them from the drapes
that used to hang in my bedroom.
- 커튼이라고?
- 아직도 많이 남았어요
- Drapes?
- They have plenty of wear left.
헬부런 성에도 갔었어요
We've been everywhere in them.
내 애들이 낡은 커튼을
입고
Are you telling me that my children
have been roaming about Salzburg...
온 거리를 누볐단 말이오?
...dressed up in nothing
but some old drapes?
굉장히 즐거운 시간이었죠
And having a marvelous time!
- 유니폼이 있잖소
-그건 죄수복이에요
- They have uniforms.
- Forgive me, straitjackets.
옷을 더럽힐까봐
놀지도 못해요
They can't be children
if they worry about clothes--
그런 말 못 들었소
They don't complain.
아빠를 사랑해서죠,
무섭기도 하고...
They don't dare.
They love you too much and fear--
더이상 듣기 싫소
Don't discuss my children.
애들과 같이 있지 않으니까-
You've got to hear,
you're never home--
듣기 싫다고 말했소!
I don't want to hear more!
알아요, 그래도 들으세요
I know you don't, but you've got to!
- 리즐은 더 이상
- 그만 해!
- Liesl's not a child.
- Not one word--
아이가 아닌 여자란 걸
아셔야 돼요
Soon she'll be a woman
and you won't even know her.
프레드릭에겐 남자가
되는 법을 가르쳐 줘야돼요
Friedrich wants to be a man
but you're not here to show--
내 아들이니 상관 마요
Don't you dare tell me--
브리지타는 얘기 상대가
필요하고
Brigitta could tell you about him.
She notices everything.
커트는 겉과 달리
상처를 받았어요
Kurt acts tough to hide the pain
when you ignore him...
아빠의 무관심 때문에
...the way you do all of them.
루이자는 모르겠지만
Louisa, I don't know about yet.
사랑이 필요해요
제발 모두를 사랑해 주세요
The little ones just want love.
Please, love them all.
더 이상 듣기 싫소
I don't care to hear more.
- 아직 안 끝났어요!
- 그러십니까, 대령님?
- I am not finished yet, captain!
- Oh, yes, you are, captain!
선생
Fr?lein.
지금 당장 짐을 싸서
수녀원으로
You will pack
your things this minute...
돌아가시오
...and return to the abbey.
무슨 소리요?
What's that?
노래 소리예요
It's singing.
그건 나도 알아요
누구 노래냐고요?
Yes, I realize it's singing.
But who is singing?
당신 아이들이오
The children.
내 아이들이?
The children?
부인을 위해
연습했어요
I taught them something to sing
for the baroness.
♪ 호수에서 나무로
My heart wants to sing
Every song it hears
♪ 나르는 새의
Every song that it hears
♪ 날갯짓처럼
My heart wants to beat like the wings
Of the birds that rise
♪ 내 마음은
From the lake to the trees
♪ 뛰놀고
To the trees
♪ 미풍에 실려오는
종소리처럼
My heart wants to sigh
Like a chime that flies
♪ 내 마음도 흔들리네
From a church on a breeze
♪ 시냇물이 돌 위로
To laugh like a brook
When it trips and falls
♪ 흩어지는 소리처럼
Over stones on its way
♪ 경쾌하게
On its way
♪ 밤새 노래하네
To sing through the night
♪ 기도하는 종달새처럼
Like a lark who is learning to pray
♪ 마음이 외로워질 때면
I go to the hills
♪ 언덕에 올라와
When my heart is lonely
♪ 여기서
I know I will hear
♪ 추억의 노래를 듣겠지
What I've heard before
♪ 그 음악소리
My heart will be blessed
♪ 내 마음에 축복이 되어
With the sound of music
♪ 한번 더
And I'll sing
♪ 불러보고 싶어
Once more
에델바이스구나!
Edelweiss!
노래를 잘한다고는
안 했잖아요
You never told me how enchanting
your children are.
잠깐만
Don't go away.
마리아 선생
Fr?lein.
내 행동이
I...
잘못 됐소,
용서하시오
...behaved badly. I apologize.
제 말이 지나쳤어요
그게 단점이죠
I'm far too outspoken.
It's one of my worst faults.
당신이 옳았소
You were right.
내가 애들을 몰랐소
I don't know my children.
시간은 있어요
가까워지길 바래요
There's still time, captain.
They want so much to be close to you.
선생이 음악을
되찾아 준거요
And you brought music back
into the house.
잊고 있었는데
I'd forgotten.
선생
Fr?lein.
가지 마시오
I want you to stay.
부탁이오
I ask you to stay.
- 제가 도움이 된다면요
- 이미 도움이 됐소
- If I could be of any help.
- You have already.
그 이상이죠
More than you know.
마타
Marta.
커튼 올려!
Curtain!
♪ 높은 언덕에 외로운
염소지기가 살았는데
High on a hill was a lonely goatherd
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
♪ 그 소년의 목소리가
하도 우렁차서
Loud was the voice
Of the lonely goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
♪ 멀리 떨어진 마을의
사람들도 들을 수 있었네
Folks in a town
That was quite remote heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
♪ 유쾌하고 맑은 소년의
목소리를 들었네
Lusty and clear
From the goatherd's throat heard
Lay odl lay odl loo
Ho ho lady odlee ho
Ho ho lady odl lay
Ho ho lady odl lee ho
Lady odl lee ho lay
마타, 마타!
Marta. Marta!
왕자님도!
Gretl, the prince!
♪ 성벽 다리 위의 왕자님도
그 소리를 들었네
A prince on the bridge
Of a castle moat heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
♪ 다리 위에 짐을 진
사람들도 들었네
Men on a road
With a load to tote heard
Lay odl lay odl loo
♪ 식탁에 앉아있던
사람들도 들었네
Men in the midst
Of a table d'h?e heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
♪ 거품 많은 맥주를
마시던 사람들도 들었네
Men drinking beer
With the foam afloat heard
Lay odl lay odl loo
♪ 진분홍 옷을 입은
소녀도 그 소리를 듣고서
One little girl
In a pale pink coat heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
♪ 외로운 소년에게
요들로 답해주었네
She yodeled back
To the lonely goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
♪ 소녀의 엄마도
그 소리를 들었네
Soon her mama
With a gleaming gloat heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
♪ 소녀와 염소지기의
아름다운 이중창 이었다네
What a duet for a girl and goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
- Hm hm hm hmm
- Hm hm hmm
- Odl lay hee
- Odl lay hee hee
Odl lay hee
Ho ho lady odlee ho
Ho ho lady odl lay
Ho ho lady odl lee ho
Lady odl lee ho lay
♪ 진분홍 옷을 입은
소녀도 그 소리를 듣고서
One little girl
In a pale pink coat heard
Lady odl lady odl lay woo hoo
♪ 외로운 소년에게
요들로 답해 주었네
She yodeled back
To the lonely goatherd
Lady odl lady odl loo
♪ 소녀의 엄마도
그 소리를 들었네
Soon her mama
With a gleaming gloat heard
Lady odl lady odl lay hm hm
♪ 소녀와 염소지기의
아름다운 이중창 이었다네
What a duet for a girl and goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
♪ 그들은 행복했네
Happy are they
Lady ho lady lee ho
Ho lady ho lady lady ho
♪ 이중창은 삼중창이 되었네
Soon the duet will become a trio
Lady odl lady odl loo
Odl lay hee
- Odl lay hee
- Odl lay hee hee
- Odl lay odl lay
Odl lay hee odl lay hee odl lay, hoo!
- 대단해!
- 브라보!
- Bravo!
훌륭했어!
Very good!
굉장했어!
Wonderful!
- 인형들 가져도 돼요?
- 정말요?
- Can we keep the puppets, Uncle Max?
- Yes, can we?
물론이지
Of course you may, my darlings.
청구서는 아빠에게 보내마
Why else did I tell Professor Kohner
to send the bill to your father?
아주 잘 했어요
Well done, fr?lein.
대단한 공연이었소
I really am very much impressed.
대령님 아이들인 걸요
They're your children, captain.
당신은 뭐든지 잘
하는군요
My dear, is there anything
you can't do?
좋은 수녀가 될 진
모르겠어요
Well, I'm not sure
I'll make a good nun.
무슨 일이든 도울게요
If you have any problems,
I'd be happy to help you.
여길 봐요!
Attention, everyone!
모두들 놀랄 발표가
있어요!
I have an announcement to make.
Surprise! Surprise!
드디어 민요대회에 나갈
Today, after a long
and desperate search...
합창단을 발견했습니다
...I have found a most exciting
entry for the Salzburg Folk Festival.
축하하네
Congratulations, Max.
그 대단한 팀이 누구지?
And who will you
be exploiting this time?
- 이그나 투이스 성가대?
- 틀렸어요
- The Saint Ignatius Choir?
- Guess again.
글쎄,
클롭만 성가대?
Well, let me see now.
The Klopmann Choir?
- 아니
- 아니라고?
- No, no, no, no.
- No, no?
말해 주세요
Tell us.
한 가족이 팀인데
절대 못 맞출 걸?
A singing group all in one family.
You'll never guess, Georg.
기막힌 생각이군!
What a charming idea!
어느 가족이지?
Whose family?
자네 가족
Yours.
내가 설명해 주지
They'll be the talk of the festival.
- 뭐가 우습나?
- 맥스
- Well, now, what's so funny?
- You are, Max.
자네 유머는비싸지만
꽤 재미있어
You're expensive, but very funny.
- 자네도 노랠 들었잖아!
- 안돼!
- They'll be a sensation!
- No, Max.
좋은 생각이잖아
저 정도로 잘하는데-
It's a wonderful idea.
Fresh, original.
사람들 앞에선 노래 안 해
Max! My children
do not sing in public.
제안해 본 걸세
You can't blame me for trying.
이번엔 누가 노래할래?
Children, who shall we hear
from next?
누구?
Who?
알았어
Yes.
만장일치예요
The vote is unanimous.
대령님이 하세요
You, captain.
내가요?
Me?
- 무슨 소린지 모르겠군
- 부탁드려요
- I don't understand.
- Please.
안돼
No, no, no, no.
전에는 잘 하셨다고
들었어요
I'm told that you were quite good.
- 그건 아주 오래 전이오
- 저는 기억하는 걸요
- That was a very, very long time ago.
- I remember, Father.
- 한번 해 주세요
- 듣고 싶어요
- Play us something we know.
- Oh, please, Father.
그럼
Well...
- 왜 얘기 안 했어요?
- 뭘?
- Why didn't you tell me?
- What?
내 하모니카
가져오라고요
To bring along my harmonica.
Edelweiss
♪ 에델바이스
♪ 매일 아침 내게
인사하네
Every morning you greet me
♪ 작고 흰 꽃
Small and white
Clean and bright
♪ 맑고 환하고
♪ 행복해
You look happy
♪ 보이는구나
To meet me
♪ 눈 속에서도
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
♪ 활짝 피어
♪ 영원히 살아있는
Bloom and grow forever
♪ 에델바이스
Edelweiss
♪ 내 조국에도
영원한 축복을
Bless my homeland forever
- ♪ 에델바이스
- Edelweiss
♪ 매일 아침 내게
인사하네
Every morning you greet me
- ♪ 작고 흰 꽃
- Small and white
- ♪ 맑고 환하게
- Clean and bright
♪ 날 보며
You look happy
♪ 행복해 하네
To meet me
♪ 눈 속에서도
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
♪ 활짝 피어
♪ 영원히 살아있는
Bloom and grow forever
♪ 에델바이스
Edelweiss
♪ 내 조국에도
영원한 축복을
Bless my homeland forever
자네가 원하면
끼워주겠네
Anytime you say the word, Georg,
you can be part of my new act:
본 트랩 합창단에 말야
The von Trapp Family Singers.
좋은 생각이 있어요
I have a wonderful idea, Georg.
제가 있는 동안
파티를 열어서
Let's really fill this house
with music.
집안을 음악으로
가득 채워요
You must give a grand
and glorious party for me.
- 파티?
- 네, 제발요
- A party?
- Yes, Father, please!
친구들도 만날 때가
It's high time
I met all your friends...
되지 않았어요?
...and they met me.
Don't you agree?
- 그건 그렇지만
- 승낙해 줘요!
- I see what you mean.
- Oh, please!
얘들아, 자야지
인사드려라
Children, it's bedtime.
Come now, say good night.
안녕히 주무세요
Good night, Father.
- 안녕
- 안녕, 부인
- Good night.
- Good night, Baroness Schraeder.
주무세요, 아빠
Good night, Father.
주무세요, 아저씨
Good night, Uncle Max.
제 첫 번째 파티가
될 거예요!
It'll be my first party, Father!
- 안녕하세요
- 슈나이더 부인입니다
- Captain.
- Herr Zeller. Baroness Schraeder.
- 안녕하세요
- Good evening, Herr Zeller.
- Baroness.
안녕하세요?
How do you do? Good evening.
아직도 오스트리아 국기가
있으니 어찌 된 거요?
Did you notice the obvious
display of the Austrian flag?
여자들이 너무 아름다워
The women look so beautiful.
못 생긴 거 같은데
I think they look ugly.
여자가 무서워서 그러지?
You're just scared of them.
웃기지 마,
어른들이나 그렇지
Silly, only grown-up men fear women.
- 난 남자들이 아름다워
- 네가 뭘 안다고?
- I think the men look beautiful.
- How would you know?
Liesl, who are you dancing with?
언니, 누구랑 춤추는 거야?
Nobody.
혼자 추는 거야
Oh, yes, you are.
거기 있었군
May I have this dance?
같이 추실 까요?
I'd be delighted, young man.
좋아요, 신사분
Why didn't you tell me
you could dance?
춤 잘 추는 건
왜 말 안 했니?
We feared you'd make us all dance.
The von Trapp Family Dancers.
아예 가족 무용단 하라고
할까봐서요
What are they playing?
저건 무슨 춤이에요?
It's the Laendler.
An Austrian folk dance.
랜들러 인데
오스트리아 민속댄스야
- Show me.
- I haven't danced since I was little.
- 가르쳐줘요
- 아주 어렸을 때 춰봤는데
You remember. Please?
기억해 봐요
- Well...
- Please.
- 글쎄
- 어서요
All right. Come on over here.
그래, 이리 와 봐
Now you bow and I curtsy.
우선 서로 인사하고
- Like this?
- Fine. Now we go for a little walk.
- 이렇게요?
- 그래, 앞으로 나가며
One, two, three. One, two, three.
하나, 둘, 셋
One, two, three, step together.
Now, step hop, step hop.
하나, 둘, 셋
발 들고, 발 들고
Now turn under. Not quite.
손을 잡고 돌리는 거야
This way. Hop step, hop.
And under.
다시 반대로, 이렇게...
Kurt, we'll have to practice.
연습 좀 해야겠다
Do allow me, will you?
내게 넘겨라
I don't remember anymore.
더 이상 기억이 안 나요
- Your face is all red.
- Is it?
- 얼굴이 빨개졌어요
- 그래?
I don't suppose I'm used to dancing.
춤 춰 본지가 오래돼서...
Why, that was beautifully done.
아주 아름다웠어요
What a lovely couple you make.
멋진 커플이었고요
It's time the children
said good night.
애들에게 작별인사를
시켜야겠소
We'll be in the hall.
홀에 있겠어요
- We have something special prepared.
- Right!
- 특별한 걸 준비했어요
- 네!
Yes, come on!
가자!
All that needless worrying, Georg.
괜한 걱정을 했군요
You thought you wouldn't find
a friend at the party.
파티에 친구가
없을 거라더니
- A bit chilly out tonight, isn't it?
- Oh, I don't know.
- 오늘밤은 좀 춥군
- 글쎄요
It seemed rather warm to me.
전 오히려 더운데요
Ladies and gentlemen.
여러분!
The children of Captain von Trapp
wish to say good night to you.
트랩가 자녀들의
작별인사입니다
There's a sad sort of clanging
From the clock in the hall
♪ 뾰족탑의 시계 종소리가
And the bells in the steeple too
♪ 울려 퍼지면
And up in the nursery
An absurd little bird
♪ 우스꽝스런 작은 새가 나와
Is popping out to say "coo-coo"
♪ "꾸꾸루" 울어대네
Coo-coo
♪ 꾸-꾸
- Regretfully, they tell us
- Coo-coo
♪ 안된 듯이 말하면서
- But firmly they compel us
- Coo-coo
♪ 작별인사를
- To say goodbye
- Coo-coo
♪ 하라고
To you
♪ 하네요
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, good night
♪ 이 구경을 계속하고 싶지만
가야만 해요
I hate to go
And leave this pretty sight
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, adieu
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
Adieu, adieu
To you and you and you
♪ 아듀, 아듀
모두들!
So long, farewell
Au revoir, auf Wiedersehen
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
I'd like to stay
And taste my first champagne
♪ 계속 있으면서
샴페인 한잔 맛보고 싶은데
- Yes?
- No.
- ♪ 괜찮아요?
- ♪ 안돼
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
♪ 한숨 지으며 떠납니다
I leave and heave a sigh
And say goodbye
Goodbye
♪ 안녕
I'm glad to go
♪ 난 자게 돼서 좋아요
I cannot tell a lie
♪ 거짓말은 못 하죠
I flit, I float
♪ 훨훨 날아 둥지로 가듯
I fleetly flee, I fly
♪ 재빨리 가겠어요
The sun has gone to bed
♪ 해님도 잠자리에 들었으니
And so must I
♪ 저도 자야죠
So long
♪ 안녕
Farewell
♪ 잘 자요
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
♪ 안녕히 주무셔요
Goodbye
♪ 잘 자요
Extraordinary!
What they'd do at the festival.
훌륭했어!
대회 때도 잘 해보라고
Young lady,
I must have a word with you.
아가씨,
얘기 좀 해요
Georg, you won't let this girl get away.
She must join the party.
이 분을 보내면 안돼
파티에 남게 해 주게
- No, really I--
- Stop. Stop it now.
- 하지만-
- 가만있어요
- Georg, please.
- You can if you want to, fr?lein.
- 이보게
- 선생이 원한다면
I insist.
You will be my dinner partner.
진심인데 파트너가
돼 주시오
This is business. Franz...
사업상이지만
...set another place next to mine
for Fr?lein Maria.
내 옆에 마리아 자리를
마련해 주게
- Whatever you say.
- It appears to be all arranged.
- 그러죠
- 이미 준비가 됐네
- It does.
- I'm not suitably dressed.
- 그럼요
- 옷이 형편없어서요
You can change. We'll wait.
갈아입어요
Captain, you must be very proud
of your youngsters.
얘들이
자랑스러우시겠어요
I am, thank you.
그렇습니다
Is there a more beautiful expression
of what is good in our country...
애들 목소리만큼
...than the innocent voices
of our children?
맑고 아름다운 건 없지
Oh, come now, baron.
남작
Would you have us believe that Austria
holds a monopoly on virtue?
오스트리아인 만
그런 건 아니지
Herr Zeller, some of us prefer
Austrian voices raised in song...
헤즐러씨,
흉측한 독일인을 위한
...to ugly German threats.
노래도 있습니다
The ostrich buries his head
in the sand...
타조는 죽을 때
땅에 머릴 박지
...and sometimes in the flag.
가끔은 국기도 말야
Perhaps those who would warn you that
the Anschluss is coming, and it is...
이제 곧 합병될 거란
경고를 해 두겠는데
...would get further with you by setting
their words to music.
노래로 당신에게
전해줄까?
If the Nazis take over Austria, you
will be the entire trumpet section.
나치가 들어오면
난 트럼펫 연주자가 될 거요
You flatter me.
찬양을 해주다니
Oh, how clumsy of me.
I meant to accuse you.
잘못 알아들었군
난 비난한 거요
It's very kind of you
to offer to help me, baroness.
도와주셔서 고마워요
I'm delighted, Maria.
천만에요
I really don't think I have anything
that would be appropriate.
마땅한 옷이 없을 거예요
Now where is that lovely little thing
you were wearing the other evening?
전에 대령이 눈을 못 떼던
When the captain couldn't keep
his eyes off you.
그 옷 있잖아요
Couldn't keep his eyes off me?
눈을 못 떼다뇨?
Come, my dear, we are women.
여자끼리는
Let's not pretend we don't know
when a man notices us.
남자가 보는 눈빛을 알죠
- Here we are.
- The captain notices everybody.
- 여기 있어요
- 대령님은 아실 거예요
There's no need to feel
so defensive, Maria.
너무 방어적일 필요
없어요
You are quite attractive, you know.
당신은 매력적이에요
The captain would hardly be a man
if he didn't notice you.
그걸 모른다면
남자가 아니지
Baroness, I hope you're joking.
농담하시는 거죠?
Not at all.
아니에요
I've never done a thing to--
난 그런 일이-
You don't have to, my dear.
그럴 필요 없어요
Nothing's more irresistible to a man
than a woman who's in love with him.
남녀의 사랑은
순간적이니까
- In love with him?
- Of course.
- 사랑이라고요?
- 그래요
What makes it so nice is
he thinks he's in love with you.
그는 당신을
사랑하고 있어요
But that's not true.
그렇지 않아요
Surely you've noticed the way
he looks into your eyes.
춤출 때 바라보던
눈길하며
And you know, you blushed in his arms
when you were dancing just now.
당신의 빨개진 얼굴
Don't take it to heart.
언짢아 말아요
He'll get over it soon enough,
I think.
그는 곧 잊을 거예요
Men do, you know.
남자들이란 그렇죠
Then I should go.
떠나야겠어요
I mustn't stay here.
있어선 안되겠어요
- Is there something I can do to help?
- No, nothing.
- 도와 줄 일이라도?
- 없어요
Yes.
있어요
Don't say a word to the captain.
대령님께는 아무 말
말아주세요
No, I wouldn't dream of it.
절대 말 안 할게요
Goodbye, Maria.
잘 가요
I'm sure you'll make a very fine nun.
훌륭한 수녀가
될 거예요
Champagne, darling.
샴페인 줘요
I feel like celebrating. Cheers.
축배를 들고 싶어요
건배!
- You know something.
- Perhaps.
- 뭔가 있군
- 아마도
If you're so clever, tell me how to
get fr?lein to influence Georg.
어떻게 하면 마리아가
게요그를 설득하게 할까?
I want those children in the festival.
대회에 나가게 해야
되는데
Elsa, this is important to Austria.
오스트리아와 당신을
위해서
Wouldn't do you any harm either.
나쁘지 않겠죠
I thought of that.
물론이지
Well, if it's a matter of influence...
그 일을
...maybe the one you have
to be talking to is me.
설득시킬 사람은
바로 나예요
- 둘
- 셋
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- 넷
- 다섯
- Six.
- Seven.
- 여섯
- 일곱
Eight.
여덟
- Four.
- Two.
- 넷
- 둘
- Seven.
- Five.
- 일곱
- 다섯
- Two.
- Six.
- 둘
- 여섯
Isn't this fun?
재미있지?
- Four.
- I'm number five.
- 넷
- 전 다섯이에요
- Oh, yes.
- Eight.
- 그래
- 여덟
- Two.
- Four.
- 둘
- 넷
Six.
여섯
Two.
둘
Baroness Schraeder, do you mind
if we stop now? We're tired.
이제 그만해도 될까요?
힘들어요
Whatever you want, dear.
그러려무나
We'll do it again tomorrow.
내일 또 하자
The country's so restful, isn't it?
시골이라 정말 아늑하죠?
Have some lemonade.
레모네이드 마셔요
There must be an easier way.
쉬운 길도 있을 텐데
I get a fiendish delight thinking
of you as the mother of seven.
일곱 아이의 엄마라니
잔인한 기쁨이군
How do you plan to do it?
어떻게 키울 거요?
Darling, haven't you ever heard...
기숙학교라고
...of a delightful little thing
called boarding school?
들어 본 적 있어요?
Baroness Machiavelli.
권모술수가 능하시군
Uncle Max, where's Father?
아저씨!
아빠는 어디 계셔요?
I think he's in the house.
집 안에 계실 거야
What's the matter
with all you gloomy pussies?
왜 그렇게 우울하니?
- Nothing.
- I know. Let's have a rehearsal.
- 아니에요
- 그럼 연습이나 더 하자
What for?
뭐하러요?
Let's make believe we're on-stage
at the festival.
무대에 섰다고
생각해보자
- I don't feel like singing.
- Not without Fr?lein Maria.
- 노래하기 싫어요
- 마리아 선생님 없이는요
Liesl, get the guitar.
Come on, Marta.
리즐, 기타를 가져와
어서 해보자
Everybody into the group.
Get in your places.
자기 자리를 알지?
Now be cheerful, right?
Give us the key, Liesl.
리즐, 음을 맞추고
Now, impress me.
자, 실력을 발휘해 봐
Gretl, why don't you sing?
그래틀, 왜 안 부르니?
- I can't. I've got a sore finger.
- But you sang so beautifully at the party.
손가락이 아파서
안되겠어요
파티 땐 잘 했잖아?
다시 들려주렴
Come on, all of you. Try something
you know. Enjoy it. Be cheerful.
활기찬 걸로 해봐
All right, Liesl.
리즐!
The hills are alive
♪ 산들은 음악소리로
With the sound of music
♪ 살아 움직인다네
With songs they have sung
♪ 수 천년 동안
For a thousand years
♪ 불러 온 노래들로
The hills fill my heart
♪ 산들은 그 음악소리로
With the sound of music
♪ 내 마음을 채운다네
날 위해 노래하는 거야
They wanted to sing for me,
bless their hearts.
That's lovely, lovely.
Don't stop.
좋구나, 계속해 봐
- Something long and cool, Georg?
- No, thank you, darling.
- 시원한 것 드릴까요?
- 아니, 됐어
- Father?
- Yes, Brigitta?
- 아빠?
- 왜 그러니?
Is it true Fr?lein Maria
isn't coming back?
마리아 선생님은
정말 안 와요?
Yes, I suppose it's true.
What have we got here?
그래, 안 올 거야
뭘 마시는 거지?
- Pink lemonade.
- Laced with lemonade.
- 핑크 레모네이드예요
- 알콜이 든 것도 있네
I don't believe it, Father.
믿을 수 없어요
- What?
- About Fr?lein Maria.
- 뭐가?
- 선생님이 가신 거요
Oh, Fr?lein Maria!
마리아 선생!
Didn't I tell you what her note said?
I'm sure I did.
편지를 읽어 줬잖아?
아닌가?
She said she missed her life
at the abbey.
수녀원 생활 때문에
She had to leave us.
가야만 한대
And that's all there is to it.
그게 전부야
I think I'm brave enough to try
some of that.
맛 좀 볼까?
- She didn't even say goodbye.
- She did in her note.
- 우리에겐 인사도 없었어요
- 편지에 섰잖니
That isn't the same thing.
그거랑 틀려요
Not too sweet, not too sour.
달지도 쓰지도 않아요
Just too pink.
색이 너무 진해
Father, who is our new governess
going to be?
새 가정교사로
누가 오나요?
Well...
앞으로는
...you're not going to have
a governess anymore.
가정교사는 오지 않는다
- We're not?
- No.
- 안 와요?
- 그래
You're going to have a new mother.
새 엄마가 계실 테니까
A new mother?
새 엄마요?
We talked about it last night.
It's all settled.
어젯밤에 결정했다
And we're all going to be very happy.
우린 행복해질 거야
Well, all right, all right.
Run off and play.
가서들 놀아라
Yes, my children?
무슨 일이세요?
- My name is Liesl.
- Yes, Liesl?
- 저는 리즐인데요
- 그런데요?
We, my brothers and sisters,
want to see Fr?lein Maria.
동생들과 마리아 선생님을
만나러 왔어요
Fr?lein Maria?
마리아 선생님?
Oh, Maria.
마리아!
Come in, please.
들어오세요
여기서 기다려요
Wait here.
I'm Sister Margaretta. I understand
you inquired about Maria.
전 마가렛 수녀예요
마리아를 왜 찾는 거죠?
We have to see her.
Will you tell her we're here?
선생님을 만나야 돼요
전해주세요
- I'm afraid I can't do that.
- But you've got to!
- 어려울 것 같은데
- 할 말이 있어요
- She's our governess.
- We want her back.
- 저희 가정교사였어요
- 돌아오길 바래요
She didn't even say goodbye.
작별인사도 못했어요
All we want to do is talk to her.
그냥 얘기만 할게요
I'm very sorry,
but Maria is in seclusion.
마리아는 지금 수련중이라
- She hasn't been seeing anyone.
- She'll see us.
- 만날 수가 없어요
- 선생님도 만나고 싶어할 걸요?
I want to show her my finger.
제 손가락을 보여
줘야 해요
Some other time, dear.
나중에 보여주거라
I'll tell her you were here.
왔었다고 전해줄게
- It was sweet of you to call.
- We have to speak to her!
- 와 줘서 고마워요
- 할 말이 있어요!
Run along, children.
Run along home.
돌아가요
I'm sure she'd like to see us.
만나게 해 주세요
Sister Margaretta, please.
수녀님, 제발
- Goodbye, children.
- Sister Margaretta, may we, please?
- 잘 가요
- 수녀님, 제발
What was that about, Sister?
무슨 일인가요?
The von Trapp children,
Reverend Mother.
본 트랩가 애들이에요
They want to see Maria.
마리아를 보러 왔대요
Has she spoken yet?
Has she told you anything?
아직도 아무 말을
안 해요?
She doesn't say a word,
Reverend Mother, except in prayer.
전혀요
기도만 하고 있어요
Poor child.
가엾게도
It's strange.
She seems happy to be back here...
이상해요, 돌아오면
좋아할 줄 알았는데
...and yet she's unhappy too.
우울해 있어요
Perhaps I have been wrong
in leaving her alone so long.
너무 오랫동안
나가있었어요
Bring her to me,
even if she's not yet ready.
준비가 안됐어도
내게 오라고 해요
Yes, Reverend Mother.
네, 원장 수녀님
Sister Augusta, take our new postulant
to the robing room.
새 견습 수녀에게
예복을 입혀주세요
God bless you, my daughter.
축복이 있기를
Yes, bring her in.
들여보내요
You've been unhappy. I'm sorry.
안 좋아 보이는구나
Reverend Mother.
원장 수녀님
Why did they send you back to us?
무슨 일로
돌아오게 됐지?
They didn't send me back. I left.
제 스스로 온 거예요
Sit down, Maria.
앉아라
Tell me what happened.
무슨 일이 있었지?
I was frightened.
전 두려웠어요
- Frightened? Were they unkind to you?
- Oh, no!
- 그들이 나쁘게 대해줬나?
- 아뇨!
No, I was confused. I felt...
마음이 너무
혼란스러워서...
I've never felt that way before.
거긴 너무 혼란스러워
I couldn't stay. I knew that here
I'd be away from it. I'd be safe.
안전한 이곳으로
온 거예요
Maria, our abbey is not to be used
as an escape.
이곳은 피난처가 아니야
What is it you can't face?
무슨 문제가 있었지?
I can't face him again.
그 분을 다시 볼 수가
없어요
Him?
그 분이라니?
Thank you, Sister Margaretta.
마가렛 수녀는 가 봐요
Captain von Trapp?
본 트랩 대령 말인가?
- Are you in love with him?
- I don't know!
- 그를 사랑하나?
- 모르겠어요!
I don't know. I--
정말 몰라요!
The baroness said I was.
She said that he was in love with me.
슈나이더 부인은 그 분이
나를 사랑한댔지만
But I didn't want to believe it.
믿지 않아요
There were times we looked
at each other.
서로 바라 볼 때는
I could hardly breathe.
숨이 멎는 것 같았지만요
- Did you let him see your feelings?
- I don't know.
- 그런 감정을 보여줬나?
- 저도 모르게
That's what's torturing me.
I was on God's errand.
그랬을지도 몰라서
맘에 걸려요
To have asked for his love would have
been wrong. I just couldn't stay.
주의 일꾼으로 가서
남자의 사랑이나 구하다니
I'm ready at this moment
to take my vows.
이제 제 서원을 받아주세요
- Please help me.
- Maria.
- 제발 도와주세요
- 마리아!
The love of a man and a woman is holy.
You have a great capacity to love.
남녀의 사랑도 성스러운 건데
사랑의 가능성이 보이는군
You must find out how God
wants you to spend your love.
주의 뜻이 어떤가에 달렸지
But I pledged my life to God.
I pledged my life to his service.
전 제 삶을
주님께 바쳤어요
My daughter, if you love this man,
it doesn't mean you love God less.
이성간의 사랑이 주님의
사랑을 없얘는 건 아나야
No.
아니지
You must find out.
자신의 길을 찾아서
You must go back.
돌아가도록 해요
You can't ask me to do that.
Please let me stay. I beg--
제발 그러지 마세요
- 여기 있게 해 주세요
- 마리아
이곳은 문제를
숨겨두는 곳이 아냐
These walls were not built
to shut out problems.
You have to face them.
문제들과 맞서서
You have to live the life
you were born to live.
자신의 삶을 살아야 해
Climb every mountain
♪ 모든 산을 오르며
Search high and low
♪ 높고 낮은 곳을 헤매고
♪ 여러 길을 걸어도
Follow every byway
Every path you know
♪ 알 수 있어요
Climb every mountain
♪ 모든 산을 오르며
Ford every stream
♪ 여러 강줄기를 따라
Follow every rainbow
♪ 무지개를 쫓아요
Till you find your dream
♪ 너의 꿈을 찾을 때까지
A dream that will need
♪ 너의 사랑이
All the love you can give
♪ 필요한 곳은
네가 사는
Every day of your life
♪ 모든 삶 속에 있어
For as long as you live
♪ 네가 살아가는 동안
Climb every mountain
♪ 모든 산을 오르며
Ford every stream
♪ 여러 강줄기를 따라
Follow every rainbow
♪ 무지개를 쫓아요
Till you find your dream
♪ 너의 꿈을 찾을 때까지
A dream that will need
♪ 너의 사랑이
All the love you can give
♪ 필요한 곳은
네가 사는
Every day of your life
♪ 모든 삶 속에 있어
For as long as you live
♪ 네가 살아가는 동안
Climb every mountain
♪ 모든 산을 오르며
Ford every stream
♪ 여러 강줄기를 따라
Follow every rainbow
♪ 무지개를 쫓아요
Till you find
♪ 너의 꿈을
Your dream
♪ 찾을 때까지
Now, it's not like my children
to be secretive.
우리 애들에겐
비밀이 없는데
We're not being secretive, Father.
비밀은 없어요
And it's not like my children
to be late for dinner.
왜 식사시간에 늦었지?
- We lost track of the time.
- I see.
- 시간 가는 줄 몰랐어요
- 좋아
Who's going to be the first one
to tell me the truth? Friedrich.
누가 사실을 말 할거지?
Brigitta. Liesl.
브리지타, 리즐
Where do you think we were, Father?
어디 갔었다고
생각하세요?
If you don't believe us, you must have
some idea of where you think we were.
자꾸 묻는 건
다른 이유가 있어서죠?
- Marta.
- Yes, Father.
- 마타
- 네
You tell me.
네가 얘기 해봐
Friedrich told you, Father.
We were berry picking.
오빠가 딸기 따러갔다고
말했잖아요
- I forgot! You were berry picking.
- Yes, we love berry picking.
- 그렇구나, 잊었었다!
- 네, 그래요
All afternoon?
오후 내내?
- We picked thousands.
- Thousands?
- 수 천 개를 땄어요
- 그래?
- They were all over the place.
- What kind of berries?
- 모두 따왔어요
- 어떤 걸 땄지?
- Blueberries, sir.
- Blueberries.
- 블루베리요
- 블루베리
It's too early for blueberries.
그건 철이 너무 이른데
- They were strawberries.
- Strawberries?
- 그냥 딸기였어요
- 딸기?
It's been so cold lately,
they turned blue.
너무 추워서 파랗게 됐죠
Very well. Show me the berries.
그렇구나, 딸기 좀 볼까?
- We...
- Well...
- 우리...
- 그건...
- Show me the berries you picked.
- We don't have them.
- 좀 보자꾸나
- 이젠 없어요
You don't have them?
What happened to them?
없다니, 왜?
- We...
- We ate them.
- 그러니까
- 다 먹었어요
- You ate them?
- Yes!
- 몽땅 다?
- 네, 그래요!
- They were so good.
- Delicious.
- 아주
- 맛있었어요
Very well.
그래
Since you've obviously stuffed
yourselves on thousands of berries...
그 맛있는 딸기를
수 천 개나 먹었으니
...you can't be hungry anymore,
so I'll have to tell Frau Schmidt...
저녁은 못 먹겠구나
...to skip your dinner.
음식을 치우라고
해야겠다
It's your fault.
We should have told him the truth.
다 형 때문이야
사실대로 말해야 하는 건데
And made him boiling mad at us?
아빠를 화나게 만들려고?
It's better than starving to death.
배고파 죽는 것 보단 나아
We didn't do anything wrong.
We just wanted to see her.
우린 잘못 없어
선생님을 보고 싶었을 뿐이야
My stomach's making noises.
꼬르륵 소리가 나
The least they could have done
was to let us say hello.
인사도 못하게 할 건
없잖아
- I wonder what grass tastes like.
- I feel awful.
- 풀은 맛이 어떨까?
- 난 기분이 나빠
선생님이 기분 나쁠 때
부르던 노래 기억 나?
When Fr?lein Maria wanted to feel
better she used to sing that song.
해 보자
Let's try it.
♪ 장미 꽃잎의 빗방울과
Raindrops on roses
And whiskers on kittens
♪ 아기 고양이 수염
♪ 빛나는 주전자
Bright copper kettles
♪ 예쁜 장갑
And warm woolen mittens
♪ 잘 포장 된
소포꾸러미들
Brown paper packages
Tied up with strings
♪ 이게 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
♪ 왜 기분이 나아지지 않지?
Why don't I feel better?
♪ 청색 띠의
Girls in white dresses
♪ 하얀 옷의 소녀들
With blue satin sashes
Snowflakes that stay
On my nose and eyelashes
♪ 코와 눈썹 위에
떨어진 눈송이들
- ♪ 봄기운에 녹은
- 선생님이다!
- Silver white winters
- Fr?lein Maria's back!
That melt into springs
♪ 은빛 겨울 풍경
♪ 이게 내가 좋아하는
것들이지
These are a few of my favorite things
When the dog bites
When the bee stings
♪ 개에게 물리고
벌에 쏘여서
♪ 마음이 슬플 때도
When I'm feeling sad
I simply remember my favorite things
♪ 좋은 것들만 생각한다면
And then I don't feel
♪ 즐거워 질 수
♪ 있겠지
So bad
- 만나서 너무 반갑다
- 보고 싶었어요
- I'm so glad to see you.
- We missed you.
I missed you.
나도 그랬어
- 커트는?
- 배고파요
- Kurt, how are you?
- Hungry.
- 손가락은 왜 그러니?
- 물렸어요
- What happened to your finger?
- It got caught.
- 뭐한테?
- 프레드릭 오빠 이빨이오
- Caught in what?
- Friedrich's teeth.
- 리즐은 어때?
- 좋아요
- Liesl, you all right?
- Just fair.
- 전보는 많이 오고?
- 안 와요
- Any telegrams been delivered lately?
- None at all.
이젠 잊었어요
학교나 빨리 가고 싶어요
But I'm learning to accept it.
I'll be glad when school begins.
학교를 피난처로 삼으면 안돼
정면으로 맞서라고
Liesl, you can't use school to escape
your problems. You have to face them.
얘기해 줄 게 많구나
I have so much to tell you.
- We have things to tell you too.
- I'm sure.
우리도 많아요
The most important thing is
that Father is going to be married.
중요한 일은 아빠가
결혼한다는 거예요
Married?
결혼?
Yes, to Baroness Schraeder.
네, 슈나이더 부인과요
Oh, I see.
그렇구나
Father, look!
Fr?lein Maria's back!
아빠, 보세요!
Fr?lein Maria's back from the abbey.
선생님이 오셨어요
Good evening, captain.
안녕하세요, 대령님
Good evening.
안녕하시오
Everyone inside for dinner.
모두 들어가 저녁 먹어라
Dinner!
저녁이다!
왜 아무 말 없이 떠난 거요?
애들에게까지도
You left without saying goodbye.
Even to the children.
It was wrong of me. Forgive me.
그건 정말 죄송해요
왜 그랬소?
Why did you?
묻지 마세요
지나간 일이니까요
Please don't ask me.
The reason no longer exists.
마리아, 돌아왔군요
Fr?lein Maria, you've returned.
Isn't it wonderful, Georg?
정말 잘 됐네요
I wish you every happiness, baroness.
두 분의 행복을 빌겠어요
You too, captain.
The children say you're to marry.
결혼 얘기 들었어요
Thank you, my dear.
고마워요
이곳에 머물거죠?
You are back to stay?
새 교사를 구할 때까지 만요
Only until arrangements can be made
for another governess.
여기 계셨군요
There you are.
쉬니젤 요리 말인데요
I must speak to cook
about the schnitzel.
아주 맛있었어요
It is entirely too delicious
for my figure.
그래서 식사 때
조용하셨어요?
And it makes you much too quiet
at the dinner table.
아니면 포도주 때문에?
Or was it the wine?
그런 것 같소
Undoubtedly the wine.
결혼 선물 때문에
You have no idea
the trouble I'm having...
제가 고민하는 거
모르시죠?
...trying to decide on
a wedding present for you.
물론 나 하나로
만족 하시겠지만
Oh, I know. I'm enough.
하지만 원하면
기회를 드리죠
But I do want you to have
some little trifle for the occasion.
작은 만년필로 할까
했는데
At first I thought
of a fountain pen...
그건 갖고 있고
...but you've already got one.
프랑스 남부 저택은
Then I thought perhaps a villa
in the south of France...
포장을 못하니까 안되고
...but they are so difficult
to gift-wrap.
지중해에 띄울
Oh, Georg, how do you
feel about yachts?
요트는 어때요?
A long, sleek one
for the Mediterranean...
아니면 욕조에
띄울 돛단배?
...or a tiny one
for your bathtub, huh?
- 엘사
- 신혼 여행은
- Elsa.
- Where to go on our honeymoon?
어디로 가죠?
Now, that's a real problem.
세계 일주가 어떨까요?
A trip around the world
would be lovely. And then I said:
더 좋은데가 있을까요?
"Oh, Elsa, there must be
someplace better to go."
- 걱정 마세요
- 엘사
- But don't worry, darling, I'll--
- Elsa.
네
Yes, Georg.
다 필요 없소
It's no use...
당신과 나 말이오
...you and I.
어제는 충동적이었소
I'm being dishonest to both of us...
당신에게도 옳지 않고
...and utterly unfair to you.
- 두 사람이 결혼얘기를 할 땐-
- 됐어요
- When two people talk of marriage--
- No, don't.
그만 하세요
Don't say another word, please.
저도 생각을 해 봤어요
You see, there are other things
I've been thinking of.
당신이 내게 맞지 않는걸
알았어요
Fond as I am of you, I really don't
think you're the right man for me.
당신은 너무 독립적이에요
You're much too independent.
난 나만을 원하는 사람이
필요해요
And I need someone
who needs me desperately...
아니면 내 돈이라도
원하든지
...or at least needs
my money desperately.
그 동안 즐겁게 해줘서
정말 고마워요
I've enjoyed every moment we've had
together and I do thank you for that.
이제
Now, if you'll forgive me...
짐을 싸서
...I'll go inside,
pack my little bags...
비엔나로 돌아가겠어요
...and return to Vienna
where I belong.
저 밖에
And somewhere out there...
어딘가 있는 아가씨는
수녀가
...is a young lady who, I think...
될 수 없겠죠?
...will never be a nun.
그럼 잘 있어요
Auf Wiedersehen, darling.
뭐 하시오?
Hello.
당신이 여기 있을 줄
알았소
I thought I just might find you here.
무슨 일이 있나요?
Was there something you wanted?
아니, 앉아요
No, no, no. Sit down, please.
앉아요
Please.
앉아도 되겠죠?
May I?
물어볼 게 두 가지 있소
You know, I was thinking
and I was wondering two things:
왜 수녀원으로 돌아갔으며
Why did you run away to the abbey?
왜 다시 돌아온 거요?
And what was it
that made you come back?
제 책임을 다하려고
Well, I had an obligation
to fulfill...
온 것뿐이에요
...and I came back to fulfill it.
그게 다요?
Is that all?
아이들도 보고 싶었고
And I missed the children.
네
Yes.
- 아이들만?
- 아뇨, 네!
- Only the children?
- No. Yes.
- 그게 잘못인가요?
- 아니오, 그렇지 않소
- Isn't it right that I missed them?
- Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
난 단지...
I was only hoping that perhaps you...
그러니까...
Perhaps you might...
뭐죠?
Yes?
당신이 떠나버리자
전과 같지 않고
Well, nothing was the same
when you were away...
엉망이 되어 버려서
...and it'll be all wrong again
after you leave...
당신 맘이 바뀌길 바랬소
...and I just thought perhaps
you might change your mind.
부인이 잘
해나가시겠죠
Well, I'm sure the baroness will be
able to make things fine for you.
마리아
Maria...
- 부인은 이제 없소
- 없다고요?
- There isn't going to be any baroness.
- There isn't?
그래요
No.
무슨 뜻이죠?
I don't understand.
우리는 파혼했소
Well, we've called off our engagement,
you see, and--
- 안됐군요
- 정말 그렇게 생각해요?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Yes. You are?
- 정말이세요?
- 그렇소
- You did?
- Yes.
어떻게 다른 사람을
사랑하면서
Well, you can't marry someone
when you're...
결혼할 수 있겠소?
...in love with someone else...
그렇지 않소?
...can you?
원장 수녀님이 늘
그러셨죠
The Reverend Mother always says:
"한쪽 문이 닫히면,
다른 쪽이 열린다"고
"When the Lord closes a door,
somewhere he opens a window."
What else does
the Reverend Mother say?
또 무슨 말을 했소?
That you have to look for your life.
내 삶을 찾으라고요
Is that why you came back?
그래서 돌아온 거요?
And have you found it...
찾은 것 같소?
...Maria?
마리아?
I think I have.
그런 것 같아요
I know I have.
바로 찾았어요
I love you.
사랑해
Oh, can this be happening to me?
이제야 행복을 찾은 것
같아요
Perhaps I had a wicked childhood
♪ 난 심술궂은 어린 시절과
Perhaps I had a miserable youth
♪ 초라한 사춘기를 보냈어요
But somewhere
In my wicked, miserable past
♪ 그런 심술궂고 초라한
과거 어딘가에
There must have been a moment of truth
♪ 진실된 순간이 있었나 봐요
For here you are
Standing there loving me
♪ 날 사랑하여
서 있는 당신
Whether or not you should
♪ 그래야만 하는진
모르겠지만
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
♪ 내 어린 시절 어느 순간에
I must have done something good
♪ 난 좋은 일을 한 게
틀림없어요
Nothing comes from nothing
♪ 아무 이유 없이는
Nothing ever could
♪ 어떤 것도 얻지 못해요
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
♪ 내 어린 시절 어느 순간에
I must have done something good
♪ 분명 난 좋은 일을
했나봐요
Do you know when I first
started loving you?
언제부터 당신을 사랑하게
됐는지 아시오?
That night at dinner, when you sat
on that ridiculous pine cone.
솔방울 위에
앉을 때부터요
What?
네?
I knew the first time you blew
that silly whistle.
난 바보 같은 호루라기를
불었을 때죠
Oh, my love.
내 사랑
For here you are
Standing there loving me
♪ 날 사랑하여
서 있는 당신
Whether or not you should
♪ 그래야만 하는 진
모르겠지만
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
♪ 내 어린 시절 어느 순간에
I must have done something good
♪ 분명 난 좋은 일을
했나봐요
Nothing comes from nothing
♪ 아무 이유 없이는
Nothing ever could
♪ 어떤 것도 얻지 못해요
So somewhere in my youth
♪ 내 어린 시절 어느 순간에
Or childhood
♪ 그 시절에
I must have done something
♪ 분명 난 좋은 일을
했나봐요
Something good
♪ 좋은 일을
Maria.
마리아
Is there anyone I should go to,
to ask permission to marry you?
내가 결혼승낙을 받으러
가야 할 사람이 있나?
- Why don't we ask--
- The children?
-있어요
- 애들?
♪ 마리아의 문제를
어떻게 풀까?
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you catch a cloud
And pin it down?
♪ 그녀를 어떻게
붙잡아 놓을까?
How do you find a word
That means Maria?
♪ 그녀를 뭐라고
표현할까요?
A flibbertigibbet
♪ 수다쟁이
A will-o'-the-wisp
A clown
♪ 사람을 홀려요
어릿광대
Many a thing you know
You'd like to tell her
♪ 그녀에게 할 말도 많고
Many a thing she ought to understand
♪ 그녀가 알아야 할 것도
많겠지
But how do you make her stay
And listen to all you say?
♪ 그녀를 데려다 어떻게
말을 듣게 만들죠?
How do you keep a wave upon the sand?
♪ 모래 위의 파도를
어떻게 잠재울까요?
Oh, how do you solve
A problem like Maria?
♪ 마리아의 문제를
어떻게 하죠?
How do you hold a moonbeam
In your hand?
♪ 달빛을 어떻게
손안에 넣을 수 있을까?
Herr Detweiler!
뎃웨일러씨!
- Heil Hitler.
- Oh, good afternoon, Herr Zeller.
- 히틀러 만세!
- 안녕하시오, 젤러씨
Perhaps you've not heard.
I am now the Gauleiter.
소식 못 들었소?
난 이제 장관이오
Heil Hitler.
히틀러 만세!
히틀러 만세
I've come from
Captain von Trapp's house.
트랩가에서 오는 길인데
The only one in the area
not flying the Third Reich flag...
합병 후에도 제3제국
국기가 걸려있지
...since the Anschluss.
않아서
- But we have dealt with that.
- I don't--
- 우리가 걸었소만
- 글쎄-
The housekeeper told me
that I would find you here.
집에선 모른다고 하고
당신이 여기
The only thing she'd tell me.
있을 거라고 하더군
What kind of information
are you looking for?
뭘 알고 싶은 거죠?
When will the captain return?
대령은 언제
돌아오는 거요?
Well, he's on his honeymoon trip.
He's not been in touch with us.
신혼여행중이라 모르겠소
Am I to believe he hasn't communicated
with his children in over a month?
애들만 놔두고 한 달이나
연락이 없단 말이요?
How many men do you know...
어떤 남자가
...who communicate with their children
while honeymooning?
신혼여행 중에
집에 연락을 하겠소?
Upon his return, he'll fill
his proper position in the new order.
돌아오면 새 명령이
기다리고 있을 거요
Naturally.
And may I congratulate you...
그렇겠죠,
어쨌든 감사합니다
...and your people in allowing the
festival to go on tonight as planned.
계획대로 대회를
열어줘서요
Why should it not go on?
Nothing in Austria has changed.
왜 못하게 하겠소?
여긴 변한 게 없소
Singing and music will
show this to the world.
음악, 노래, 모든 게
Austria is the same.
그대로요
Heil Hitler.
히틀러 만세
Come, let's go home.
어서 집에 가거라
- Why was he so cross?
- Everybody's cross these days.
- 왜 저렇게 화났죠?
- 요새는 다 그렇단다
Maybe the flag with the black spider
makes people nervous.
국기에 그려진 거미가
화나게 했나봐
- Will Father be in trouble?
- He doesn't have to be.
- 아빠에게 일이 생길까요?
- 그렇진 않을 거다
The thing to do
is to get along with everybody.
아직은 괜찮으니까
Remember that tonight at the concert.
오늘밤 음악회만 생각해라
Are we really going to sing
before a lot of people?
정말 오늘밤
사람들 앞에서 공연해요?
Look. The von Trapp Family Singers:
그럼, 봐라
본 트랩가 합창단!
Liesl, Friedrich, Louisa, Brigitta,
Kurt, Marta and Gretl.
리즐, 프레드릭, 루이자,
브리지타, 커트, 마타, 그레틀
- Why am I always last?
- Because you are the most important.
- 왜 난 항상 끝이죠?
- 가장 중요하기 때문이지
There we go.
가자
Are you sure Father will approve
of our singing in public?
아빠가 공연하는 걸
허락할까요?
He'll be pleased and proud.
자랑스러워 할거다
- Liesl, do you think so?
- Don't you trust me?
- 리즐 언니도 그렇게 생각해?
- 내 말을 안 믿니?
No.
못 믿어요
You're a very intelligent girl.
어쩜 그리 똑똑하냐?
Liesl. Liesl!
리즐, 리즐!
Rolfe!
랄프!
I'm so glad to see you.
It's been su--
정말 반가워
그 동안-
Good afternoon.
안녕
Give this to your father
as soon as he's home.
대령님께 이걸
오시는 대로 전해 줘
- He's on his honeymoon.
- I know.
- 신혼여행 중인 걸?
- 알아
- You do?
- We make it our business to know all.
- 그래?
- 우린 모든 사람의 동향을 알아
- Who's "we"?
- See that he gets it.
- "우리"라니?
-여기 있어
- What is it?
- It's a telegram from Berlin.
- 뭔데?
- 베를린에서 온 전보야
Don't you want to deliver it yourself?
오늘 밤 직접 배달하지 그래?
I'm occupied
with more important matters.
난 더 중요한 임무가 있어
And your father had better be too.
네 아빠도 그걸 원하실 거야
But, Rolfe!
하지만 랄프!
Father!
아빠다!
- We didn't expect you so soon.
- Hello, hello!
- 일찍 오셨군요
- 얘들아
We didn't expect you home
until next week!
다음주에 오실 줄 알았는데
- Did you bring souvenirs from Paris?
- Hello! How are you?
- 선물 사오셨어요?
- 잘 있었니?
Why didn't you call us?
왜 전화 안 하셨어요?
We couldn't get through.
궁금했는데
I had nothing to do with that.
난 상관없는 일이네
We came back as fast as we could.
금방 올게 기다려
Well, well, well! We missed you!
보고 싶었다!
- We missed you!
- We missed kissing you.
- 보고 싶었어요!
- 뽀뽀가 그리웠어
We missed all the noise
in the morning.
너희들 떠드는 소리도
- Mostly, we missed hearing you sing.
- Oh, you came back just in time.
- 너희 노래가 듣고 싶었어
- 마침 잘 오셨어요
Look, Fr?lein Maria--
보세요, 선생님
I mean Mother.
아니, 엄마
We're going to sing
in the festival tonight.
우린 오늘 밤
음악회에 나가요
We've been having a lovely time!
재미있을 거예요!
We've been rehearsing all--
연습 많이 했어요
Surprise! Surprise!
놀라게 해 주려고!
Surprises for you on the terrace.
더 놀랄 선물이 있다
We'll talk about this.
안에 들어가서 얘기하지
I would've told you but you were away.
I had to make a last-minute decision.
얘기하려고 했는데
여행중이라서
I was fortunate to enter them at all.
생각 끝에 접수시켰네
They'll be the talk of the festival.
Imagine, seven children in one family!
일곱 명으로 이뤄진
한 가족이라면 놀랄 거야
Max!
맥스!
Somehow I recall having made it
quite clear to you...
분명히 말하지만
우리 애들은
...how I feel about my family
singing in public!
남들 앞에선 노래 안 해
The committee was enchanted.
심사위원들도 칭찬하던데
- What did they say?
- I have never heard such enthusiasm.
- 뭐랬는데요?
- 처음 듣는 열정적인 노래랬소
- Don't you think just this once--?
- Absolutely out of the question.
- 여보, 이번 한번만-
- 절대로 안돼
- Georg, this is for Austria.
- For Austria?
- 이건 오스트리아를 위해서야
- 뭐라고?
- There is no Austria!
- But the Anschluss was peaceful.
- 이제 오스트리아는 없어!
- 합병은 평화롭게 끝났어
- Let's at least be grateful for that.
- Grateful?
- 다행이라 여겨야지
- 다행이라고?
You know, Max...
맥스
...sometimes I don't believe
I know you.
난 자네가 가끔
의심스러워
Father, I forgot.
아빠, 깜빡했는데
This is for you.
전보가 왔어요
Maria, he has got to at least pretend
to work with these people.
동조하는 척이라도
해야돼요
You must convince him.
잘 설득해 봐요
Max, I can't ask him
to be less than he is.
제가 강요할 순 없어요
Then I'll talk to him.
If the children don't sing, well...
내가 해 보지
얘들이 안 하면
...it will be a reflection
on Austria.
오스트리아의 손실이오
Oh, I know.
It wouldn't do me any good either.
내게도 물론 손실이고
Mother? That sounds so nice.
엄마라고 부르니까
- I like calling you "Mother."
- I like hearing it.
- 참 좋아요
- 나도 그래
You love Father very much.
I can tell you do.
아빠를 무척 사랑하죠?
알 수 있어요
Very much.
아주 많이
Mother, what do you do when you
think you love someone?
누군가와 사랑하다가
I mean, when you stop loving someone
or he stops loving you?
잘 안되면 어떻게 하죠?
날 사랑하지 않으면요?
Well, you cry a little.
조금 울다가
Then you wait for the sun
to come out.
다시 해가 뜨길 기다려
It always does.
해는 항상 뜨니까
There are so many things I think
I should know but I don't.
많은 것을 알아야 하는데
전 아무 것도
- I really don't.
- How can you?
- 몰라요
- 어떻게 알겠니?
어떨 땐 세상이
끝난 것 같고
- Sometimes I feel the world is ending.
- Then you feel it's just beginning?
- 그 다음엔 시작인 것 같지?
- 맞아요!
- Yes!
- It was that way with me.
그렇다면 좋아질 거야
내가 약속할게
- And for you it will be just as wonderful.
- Do you really think so?
정말 그럴까요?
♪ 넌 16살에서 17살이 되니
When you're 16 going on 17
Waiting for life to start
♪ 진정 삶을 시작할 때야
Somebody kind
Who touches your mind
♪ 어느 친절한 젊은이가
Will suddenly touch your heart
♪ 너의 마음을
사로잡을 거야
When that happens
♪ 만약 그런 일이
After it happens
♪ 생긴다면
Nothing is quite the same
♪ 분명 모든 게
달라질 거예요
Somehow I know
♪ 그가
I'll jump up and go
♪ 내 이름을 부르면
If ever he calls my name
♪ 내 가슴이 뛰겠죠
Gone are your old ideas of life
♪ 과거의 생각은 잊고
The old ideas grow dim
♪ 새로운 생각을 하게되지
Lo and behold
You're someone's wife
♪ 누군가의 아내가 되고
And you belong to him
♪ 그에게 속하게 돼
You may think this kind of adventure
♪ 이런 모험을 하게
되리라곤
Never may come to you
♪ 상상도 못 할걸
Darling, 16 going on 17
♪ 넌 16살에서 17살이 되니
Wait a year
♪ 1년 더 기다려 보렴
- I'll wait a year
- Or two
- ♪ 기다릴게요
- ♪ 아니면 2년
Just wait a year
♪ 1~2년 더 기다려
Or two
♪ 볼 게요
리즐!
What is it?
무슨 일이죠?
Berlin.
베를린에서
They've offered me a commission.
징집 명령이 왔소
I've been requested
to accept immediately...
당장 출발해서
...and report to their naval base
at Bremerhaven tomorrow.
내일 브레머헤븐 해군기지로
가라는 거야
I knew this would happen.
I didn't think it would be so soon.
예상은 했었지만
이렇게 빠를 줄 몰랐어요
To refuse them would be fatal
for all of us.
거부하면 우리 모두
화를 당하겠지만
And joining them would be unthinkable.
징집에 응하는 것도
상상 못할 일이오
Get the children all together.
애들을 다 모아요
Don't say anything to worry them.
Just get them ready.
물론 아무 얘기말고
준비 시켜요
We've got to get out of Austria...
다 함께 오스트리아와
...and this house...
이 집을 떠나는 거요
...tonight.
오늘 밤
This strains my back
and breaks my heart...
난 등뿐 아니라
마음도 아파
...when I think of the children
missing the festival.
확실한 팀이
대회에서 빠지다니
By your announcement
we'll be over the border.
나중에 얘기 해
국경을 넘을 거니까
Do you appreciate
the sacrifice I'm making?
내게 사례는 하겠지?
You have no choice.
선택의 여지가 없잖아
I know. That's why I'm making it.
알아, 그래서 돕는 거야
Why doesn't Father turn the motor on?
왜 시동을 안 걸죠?
Because he doesn't want anyone
to hear us.
소리를 안 내기 위해서야
What will Frau Schmidt and Franz say?
슈미츠 부인과 집사는
뭐랄 까요?
They'll be able to answer honestly
they didn't know anything.
누가 물어봐도
모른다고 할거야
- Will we be coming back here?
- Someday, Liesl. I do hope someday.
- 다시 돌아올 건가요?
- 언젠간 꼭 그러길 바란단다
Are Father and Uncle Max going to push
the car all the way to Switzerland?
스위스까지 계속
차를 밀고 갈 거예요?
Something wrong
with your car, captain?
차에 이상이라도 있나?
Yes, we couldn't get it started.
네, 시동이 안 걸려서요
Karl.
칼!
Fix Captain von Trapp's car
so that it will start.
시동 좀 걸어드려라
Excellent, Karl.
수고했네
I've not asked you where you
and your family are going.
어딜 가는지 안 물어봤군
Nor have you asked me why I'm here.
내가 온 이유도 안 묻고
Apparently we both suffer
from a deplorable lack of curiosity.
서로 호기심 결핍증에
걸린 것 같군
You never answered the telegram...
전보에 답장을 안 했더군
...from the Admiral of the Navy
of the Third Reich.
제3국 해군대장이
보낸 건데
I was under the impression,
Herr Zeller...
전보 내용이
...that the contents of telegrams
in Austria are private!
너무 친절해서
깊은 감명을 받았지!
At least, the Austria I know.
적어도 오스트리아 인에겐
I have my orders...
오늘 밤 당신을
...to take you
to Bremerhaven tonight...
데려오라는 명령을 받았소
...where you will accept
your commission.
명령에 따르시오
I'm afraid that's going to be
quite impossible.
그건 불가능하겠는데
You see, we...
보다시피
...all of us, the entire family,
will be...
가족 모두가 합창대회에
...singing in the festival tonight.
가는 중이라서요
As a matter of fact, we're going now.
사실 지금 가는 중이오
We couldn't possibly
let them down now.
놓칠 수 없는 대회요
- I just hope we're not too late.
- Yes.
- 늦지 않았으면 하는데요
- 그렇소
You ask me to believe that you,
Captain von Trapp...
그 말을 믿으란 말이오?
...are singing in a concert?
당신이 노래를 해?
Believe me, it will be a performance
beyond anything even I've dreamt of.
나도 전엔 믿지 않았지만
사실입니다
Like you, Herr Zeller,
I, too, am a man of hidden talents.
나도 당신처럼
숨겨둔 재능이 있거든
Yes.
그래요
Here, program.
이 프로그램을 봐요
It says only the names
of the children.
여긴 얘들 이름만 있는데
It says
the von Trapp Family Singers...
분명 본 트랩가 합창단이고
...and I am the head of
the von Trapp family, am I not?
난 본 트랩가의 가장이오
And these travel clothes
that you're all wearing?
그럼, 이 여행 옷들은 뭐지?
Our costumes, naturally.
공연의상이에요
This night air is not good
for the children's voices.
밤 공기가 애들 목소리에
안 좋아서요
Well, a slight delay in my orders
will not be serious.
잠깐 연기하는 건
괜찮겠지
Therefore...
당신도
...you will sing.
노래하겠지
You will all sing.
당신들 모두 말아야
But only because that's what I want.
내가 보고 싶으니
허락하지만
It will demonstrate that nothing
in Austria has changed.
공연이 상황을 바꿀 순 없소
And when you have finished singing...
공연이 끝나는 즉시
...you, Captain von Trapp, will be
taken to Bremerhaven.
당신을 해군기지로
송환하겠소
Now, if you will all get
into your car...
그럼, 공연장까지
...we will escort the von Trapp Family
Singers to the festival.
본 트랩 합창단을
모셔다 드리죠
No escort will be necessary.
그럴 필요 없소
필요할 거요
Necessary? A pleasure, captain.
After all, we would not want you
to get lost in the crowds.
당신이 가다가
길을 잃을 지도 모르잖소
Would we?
안 그렇소?
No.
그렇군요
♪ 솔은 꿰매는 바늘
- Sew, a needle pulling thread
- A needle pulling thread
- La, a note to follow sew
- A note to follow sew
♪ 라는 솔 다음에 음
- Tea, a drink with jam and bread
- A drink with jam and bread
♪ 시는 빵과 마시는 차
♪ 빵과 마시는 차
- Jam and bread
- With jam and bread
Tea with jam and bread
Jam and bread
Tea with jam, jam and bread
♪ 빵과 마시는 차
- With jam
- A, B, C
- ♪ 잼과 함께
- ♪ A, B, C
- With jam
- Do-re-mi
- ♪ 잼과 함께
- ♪ 도-레-미
Tea with jam and bread
♪ 잼과 함께 먹는 빵
With jam and bread
With jam
♪ 잼과 함께
And bread
♪ 먹는 빵
My fellow Austrians...
오스트리아 국민여러분!
앞으로 오랫동안
여러분을 못 뵐 겁니다
...I shall not be seeing you again,
perhaps for a very long time.
여러분도 잘 아시는
I would like to sing for you now...
노래를 부르겠습니다
...a love song.
서로 사랑을 나누면서
I know you share this love.
영원하시길 바랍니다
I pray that you will never let it die.
Edelweiss
♪ 에델바이스
Every morning you greet me
♪ 매일 아침 내게
인사하네
Small and white
♪ 작고 흰 꽃
Clean and bright
♪ 맑고 환하고
You look happy to meet me
♪ 행복해 보이는구나
Blossom of snow
♪ 눈 속에서도
May you bloom and grow
♪ 활짝 피어
Bloom and grow forever
♪ 영원히 살아있는
Edelweiss
♪ 에델바이스
Bless my homeland forever
♪ 내 조국에도
영원한 축복을
Edelweiss
♪ 에델바이스
Edel...
♪ 에델...
Small and white
♪ 작고 흰 꽃
Clean and bright
♪ 맑고 환하고
You look happy to meet me
♪ 행복해 보이는구나
Blossom of snow
♪ 눈 속에서도
May you bloom and grow
♪ 활짝 피어
Bloom and grow forever
♪ 영원히 살아있는
Edelweiss
♪ 에델바이스
Bless my homeland forever
♪ 내 조국에도
영원한 축복을
성공할 거야
I think it'll work.
I shall miss all of you.
보고 싶을 거고
내 돈도 그리울 거야
I shall miss the money
I could have made with you.
고맙습니다, 여러분
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
이제 공연은 끝났습니다
The competition has come
to its conclusion...
...except, we don't know
yet what that conclusion will be.
누가 우승할지는 모르지만
심사위원들이 결정할 동안
And while the judges
arrive at their decision...
앵콜곡을 듣겠습니다
...I have been given permission
to offer you an encore.
이제는 다시 보지 못할
트랩가의
This will be the last opportunity
the von Trapps will have...
마지막 노래입니다
...of singing together
for a long, long time.
군인들도 여기 있습니다만
Even now, officials are waiting
in this auditorium...
트랩 대령은
이제 제3국
...to escort Captain von Trapp
to his new command...
해군으로 송환될 것입니다
...in the naval forces
of the Third Reich.
본 트랩가를 다시 모시죠
곱명은
And so, ladies and gentlemen,
the family von Trapp again...
작별인사 입니다
...to bid you farewell.
There's a sad sort of clanging
From the clock in the hall
♪ 뾰족탑의 시계종소리가
♪ 울려 퍼지면
And the bells in the steeple too
♪ 우스꽝스런
작은 새가 나와
And up in the nursery
An absurd little bird
♪ "꾸꾸루" 울어대네
Is popping out to say "coo-coo"
♪ 꾸-꾸
Coo-coo
- Regretfully, they tell us
- Coo-coo
♪ 안된 듯이 말하면서
♪ 작별인사를
- But firmly they compel us
- Coo-coo
♪ 하라고
To say goodbye
♪ 하네요
To you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, good night
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
We hate to go
And miss this pretty sight
♪ 이 구경을 계속하고 싶지만
가야만 해요
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, adieu
♪ 아듀, 아듀
모두들!
Adieu, adieu
To you and you and you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
We flit, we float
♪ 훨훨 날아
We fleetly flee, we fly
♪ 둥지로 가겠어요
♪ 안녕, 잘 자요
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
♪ 해님도 잠들었으니
저도 자야죠
The sun has gone to bed
And so must I
♪ 안녕
Goodbye
♪ 편한 밤 보내세요
♪ 안녕
Goodbye
여러분, 기다리시던
결과가 나왔습니다
Ladies and gentlemen, I have here the
decision of our distinguished judges.
3등부터 시작하죠
We will start with the award
for third prize.
심사 결과 3등은
For this honor,
the judges have named...
아가사 교회의
성가 솔로 리스트입니다
...the first soloist of the choir
of St. Agatha's Church in Murback.
슈바이거 양
Fr?lein Schweiger.
Second prize
to The Toby Reiser Quintet.
2등은 토비 와이저
중창단입니다
오스트리아
영예의 1등은
And the first prize,
the highest honor in all Austria...
본 트랩 가족 합창단
...the von Trapp Family Singers.
The family von Trapp.
달아났습니다!
They're gone!
날 따라와요
Come with me.
어서 이리로
Quickly, quickly.
저 쪽에 숨도록 해요
I have a place you can hide.
천천히 가요
Slowly, slowly.
어서 문여시오
Open this gate.
안녕하세요
Good evening.
빨리 여시오
Hurry up, woman.
너희들은 이쪽으로
Two men in there.
너희들은 저쪽으로
Six of you cover the yard.
나머진 이쪽으로
You two, cover the corridor.
원장수녀님, 곤경에
빠뜨리게 해서 죄송해요
Reverend Mother, we didn't realize
we put the abbey in this danger.
그런 말하지마
여기로 오길 잘했어
No, Maria, it was right for you
to come here.
차 좀 빌릴 수 있을까요?
We thought we might borrow
your car.
아무 소용없어요
I'm afraid our car will do you
no good now.
라디오에서
I've been listening to the wires.
국경이 폐쇄됐다고
했어요
The borders have just been closed.
국경이 폐쇄됐다면
All right,
if the borders are closed...
근방에 있는 산을
넘읍시다
...then we'll drive up into the hills
and go over the mountains on foot.
- 애들은-
- 우리가 도와야지
- The children--
- We'll help them.
우리도 할 수 있어요
We can do it without help, Father.
마리아
Maria.
혼자가 아니란 걸 명심해
You will not be alone.
Remember:
"어딜 가든 내가
기도하겠어"
"I will lift up mine eyes unto
the hills from whence cometh my help."
명심할게요
Yes, Mother.
- 난 무서워
- 나도
- I'm scared.
- Me too.
주님이 함께 하시길
God be with you.
- 엄마
- 왜?
- Mother.
- Yes?
좋은 것만 생각하는
노래를 부를까요?
Would it help if we sang
about our favorite things?
안돼, 지금은 도움이 안돼
No, darling.
This is one time it would not help.
소리를 내서는 안 된단다
이리 오렴
You must be very quiet.
Hold tight to me.
지붕 쪽을 살펴봐
Let's try the roof.
랄프, 제발
Rolfe, please.
랄프, 잠깐
No, wait.
마리아
Maria.
애들과 가
Children.
당신만 체포하면 돼
It's you we want, not them.
총 내려 놔
Put that down.
움직이면 쏘겠어
Not another move,
or I'll shoot.
넌 아직 어린애야
You're only a boy.
- 저들과는 다르다고
- 거기 그대로 있어!
- You don't really belong to them.
- Stay where you are.
우리와 같이 가자
Come away with us.
늦기 전에
Before it's too late.
한발만 더 오면
죽이겠다
Not another step.
I'll kill you.
- 총 이리 내놔
- 안 들려?
- You give that to me, Rolfe.
- Did you hear me?
죽일 거라고!
I'll kill you.
랄프
Rolfe.
넌 그들처럼 되지 못해
You'll never be one of them.
중위님!
Lieutenant!
여기 있습니다!
They're here!
여기요!
They're here, lieutenant!
원장 수녀님
Reverend Mother.
죄를 지었어요
I have sinned.
저도요
I too, Reverend Mother.
무슨 죄를 지었지?
What is this sin, my children?
A dream that will need
All the love you can give
Every day of your life
For as long as you live
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find
Your dream
[ENGLISH]